时  空  恋  旅  人
我一直都知道  我家里人都有点奇怪
I aways knew we were a fairly odd family.
先说说我吧
First there was me.
太高  太瘦  太红毛
Too tall. Too skinny. Too orange.
我妈很可爱  但和其他当妈的不一样
My mum was lovely, but not like other mums.
她的性格呢  有点固执
There was something solid about her.
有点呆板  有点冷艳  总是忙忙碌碌
Something rectangular, busy and unsentimental.
她的时尚标杆是英国女王
Her fashion icon was the Queen.
我爸呢  他看上去就正常多了
Dad, well, he was more normal.
他总是那么闲
He always seemed to have time on his hands.
自从他五十岁生日那天
After giving up teaching
辞去了大学教师的工作后
university students on his 50th birthday,
要么随时陪你聊天
he was eternally available for a leisurely chat or
要么就是在乒乓大战中被我虐
to let me win at table tennis.
漂亮
Yes.
接下来是我舅舅  德斯蒙德
And then there was Mum's brother, Uncle Desmond.
总是正装打扮  总在混日子
Always impeccably dressed. He spent the days just, well,
反正有他自己的一套
being Uncle Desmond.
在家里他最有魅力了
He was the most charming
但却又傻得不行
and least clever man you could ever meet.
他思想捉摸不透  咱可懂不了
His mind was on other things, though we never found out what.
最后一位是我妹凯特琳
And then, finally there was Catherine.
又叫凯蒂或奇巧
Katie. Kit Kat. My sister.
在这个从着装到发型都中规中矩的家庭里
In a household of sensible jackets and haircuts there was this,
她简直就是个野生尤物
well, what can I call her, nature thing.
一双水灵灵的大眼
With her elfin eyes,
紫色的上衣  总是打着赤脚
her purple T-shirts and her eternally bare feet,
对于我来说  她一直都是
she was then, and still is to me,
这世界上最可爱的人
about the most wonderful thing in the world.
说到头  童年还是很快乐的
All in all, it was a pretty good childhood.
每日重复的节奏与模式
Full of repeated rhythms and patterns.
在我21岁前
By the time I was 21,
我们每天都会来海边享受下午茶
we were still having tea on the beach every single day.
丢石块打水漂  吃着三文治充饥
Skimming stones and eating sandwiches,
无论春夏秋冬  不管天气好坏
summer and winter, no matter what the weather.
每周五晚都是我们的电影之夜
And every Friday evening, a film,
也是不管天气好与坏
no matter what the weather.
直到那一年不堪回首的跨年派对
And then once a year, the dreaded New Year's Eve party.
等一会  我再去拿一瓶
Yeah, I might just get one.
你真太美了
You're absolutely gorgeous.
我叫凯蒂  我喝什么呢
I'm Katie. What am I drinking?
这杯酒可贵了
This is very expensive stuff.
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
快来  马上就12点了
Come on, it's nearly midnight.
我们要倒数了  开始倒数了
We're all going through. We're going through.
我要帮你找个...
Look, I've gotta find you a...
天啊
God!
人紧张就会犯错  没事  快来
Everyone makes little mistakes. It's fine. Come on.
6 5 4 3 2 1
6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
新年快乐
Happy New Year!
Happy New Year.
对不起
Sorry.
第二天早上醒来
And so I woke up the next morning,
酒还没醒  感到羞愧
hung-over, ashamed of myself,
没有意识到今天是
and not realising it was the day
会彻底改变人生的一天
that would change my life forever.
起床啦  蠢猪
Get up, stupid.
老爸找你
Dad wants you.
你好哇  性感睡衣
Hello. Sexy pyjamas.
蒂姆  快进来
Tim, come in.
请
Do...
坐下
Sit down.
搞得挺正式啊
That's very formal.
是这样的
Well, um, yeah.
我也有点紧张
This is an odd moment for me
因为我刚满21岁时
because I had the same moment with my father
我爸爸也和我有过这样的谈话
when I'd just turned 21,
之后我的人生就此改变了
and after it, my life was never the same,
所以我现在也挺紧张
so I approach it pretty, um, nervously.
好吧
Okay.
你好好酝酿  貌似挺神秘的
When you're ready. It's all very mysterious.
是的
Right.
蒂姆  我亲爱的儿子
Tim, my dear son, the...
简单说就是咱家的男人
The simple fact is the men in this family
一直都有一种能力
have always had the ability to...
这听起来很荒唐  做好准备
This is going to sound strange, be prepared for strangeness.
别吓坏了
Get ready for spooky time,
这可是咱家的秘密
but there's this family secret.
秘密就是咱家的男人能
And the secret is that the men in the family can
穿越时空
travel in time.
准确的说  能穿越到过去
Well, more accurately, travel back in time.
不能穿越到未来
We can't travel into the future.
这玩笑挺怪异的
This is such a weird joke.
这不是玩笑
It's seriously not a joke.
意思是  你和爷爷还有他的兄弟
So you're saying that you and granddad, and his brothers
-你们都能穿越到过去  -没错
- could all travel back in time? - Absolutely.
-你现在还能?  -是的
- And you still do? - Absolutely.
实际并没说起来那么夸张
Although it's not as dramatic as it sounds.
只能在自己的人生中穿越
It's only in my own life.
只能去我去过且还记得的地方
I can only go to places where I actually was and can remember.
很可惜  我无法暗杀希特勒
I can't kill Hitler or shag Helen of Troy,
无法和特洛伊的海伦滚床单
unfortunately.
好  打住
Okay, stop.
如果是真的  当然这不可能
If it's true, which it isn't.
就是真的
Although it is.
显然不是
Although it isn't, obviously.
-假设是真的  虽然其实是假的  -是真的
- But if it was, which it's not. - Which it is.
不可能
Which it isn't.
但若是真的  那我要怎样...
But if it was, how would I...
其实很简单的
The "How" Is the easy bit, in fact.
你找个黑暗的地方
You go into a dark place,
壁柜里是最佳场所
big cupboards are very useful generally.
必要时用厕所
Toilets, at a pinch.
然后像我这样握紧拳头
Then you clench your fists like this.
想着你要去的地方
Think of the moment you're going to
然后你就穿越过去了
and you'll find yourself there.
当然还会有些磕磕碰碰什么的
After a bit of a stumble and a rumble and a tumble.
很冷静嘛
Is as good a reaction as any.
我那时大喊了一句"我操"  而且是在70年代
I think I plumped for "Fuck!" But it was the '70s.
别吹了  完全就是开玩笑的
No, this is so obviously a joke.
都说了不是玩笑
It's not a joke.
干嘛我要骗...
Why would I lie to someone I'm...
我喜欢的人
fairly fond of?
好吧
Okay.
但是  要是我在壁柜里握紧拳头
But, when I come back downstairs
出来还是老样子
after standing in a cupboard with my fists clenched,
那你可就麻烦了
you're gonna be in so much trouble.
走着瞧
Well, let's see, shall we?
对了  试着做些有趣的事情
And, Tim, try and do something interesting.
你就有大麻烦了
So much trouble.
我说到做到
I mean it. Really.
试试吧
Right.
没醉吧  蒂姆
You all right, Tim?
没  很好  很清醒  很棒
Yes. Yeah. Good, ace. Yeah.
那好  快来
Good, come on.
马上就12点了  我们要找到...
It's nearly midnight and we've got to find...
小心小心
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
马上十二点了
Whoo! Midnight.
10 9 8 7
10, 9, 8, 7,
6 5 4 3 2 1
6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
新年快乐
Happy New Year!
谢谢你  蒂姆
Thank you, Tim.
不用谢  波莉
You're welcome, Polly.
老妈知道吗
Does Mum know?
不知道
Not a whistle.
奇怪了  那万一...
Strange. And what about the whole...
产生蝴蝶效应是吧  怎么说呢
Butterfly effect thing. What can I say?
目前看来我们还没毁坏人类文明
We don't seem to have messed up civilisation yet.
今年会很复杂
It's gonna be a complicated year.
今生也会很复杂
It's gonna be a complicated life.
那你都回去干了些什么
What have you done with it?
对我来说  就是看书  看书  看书
For me, it's books, books, books.
把一个人想看的书都看完了
I've read everything a man could wish to.
看了两遍  狄更斯的三遍
Twice. Dickens three times.
你想干些什么
Any first thoughts?
我想
Well, I suppose apart from
除了弄个更潮流的发型外
getting a slightly better haircut...
很明显还要赚很多钱
Money would be the obvious thing.
这亦好亦坏
Very mixed blessing.
你爷爷这辈子就被这样毁了
Utterly screwed up your grandfather's life.
孤独终老
Left him without love or friends.
我也从未遇到过真正快乐的富豪
I've never bumped into a genuinely happy rich person.
如果可以不用工作也不错
It would be nice not to have to work.
不行  它是万劫之首啊
No, that's a real recipe for disaster.
看看你叔叔弗雷德就知道了
Look what happened to Uncle Fred.
他怎么了
What happened to Uncle Fred?
一事无成
Absolutely sod all.
混日子
Wasted his life.
必须把运用这种能力
You have to use it for things that you really think
把人生变成你真正想要的样子
will make your life the way you want it to be.
真的  要好好考虑
Come on, really think about this.
其实嘛
Well,
老实说  现在我只希望
to be honest, I suppose, at the moment,
这种超能力能帮我找到个女朋友
it would be just great if it could help me get a girlfriend.
这可不容易
Massive.
是啊  重头戏
The mothership.
我一直渴望得到真爱
For me, it was always gonna be about love.
今年夏天我就陷入了爱情的泥潭中
And that summer I walked into the eye of the storm.
她叫夏洛特
Her name was Charlotte.
是我妹那渣男友吉米的表妹
Cousin of Kit Kat's handsome but nasty boyfriend Jimmy.
她在我家待了整整两个月
And she was staying for two whole months.
就这个  不是全部
Just one. Not both of them.
蒂姆
Tim,
可以帮我擦防晒霜吗
will you do my back?
当然
Absolutely!
很殷勤嘛
Very keen!
不  不
Whoa! No. No.
不  不  不
No. No, no. No, no, no.
-弄到头发上了?  -是的
- Is it in my hair? - Yes!
蒂姆  可以帮我擦防晒霜吗
Tim. Will you do my back?
可以  等一会儿
Sure. Just give us a sec.
好的
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
来了
Now...
好舒服啊
Ooh. Nice.
我最拿手了
It's my area.
这是一个又晒又折磨人的夏天
It was a summer of suntan and torture.
我之所以叫我那呆瓜朋友杰来打网球
I invited my foolish friend Jay around for tennis
是因为我原以为他能衬托出我很厉害
because I thought he'd make me look good.
但我错了
I was wrong!
-你怎么打的啊  -抱歉抱歉
- What are you doing? - No.
夏洛特把我俩玩得团团转
Charlotte just made both of us look like idiots.
运气不好啊  蒂姆
Bad luck, Tim.
妈的  这怎么能让人集中精神打球嘛
How the hell are you meant to concentrate on your game?
这样下去
How are you meant to live your life
让我怎么过今后的生活啊
with this sort of shit going down?
情况一直这样
It never got better until suddenly
直到快来不及了
it was almost too late.
夏洛特  这是我们最后一次午餐了
Well, Charlotte, our final lunch.
不要
No!
有你的这个夏天很开心
And it's been really, really lovely having you all summer.
是的
It has.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
真的  真的很开心
It has. It really has.
德斯蒙德  很开心吧
Hasn't it, Desmond?
你说啥
Beg your pardon?
这个夏天有夏洛特很开心
Lovely having Charlotte here all summer.
夏洛特? 谁是夏洛特啊
Charlotte? Who's Charlotte?
长点记性  夏洛特就坐在你旁边
Come on, darling. Charlotte, sitting next to you.
是哦  记起来了  你是夏洛特
Yes, of course. Of course. Charlotte.
很高兴认识你
Lovely to meet you.
蒂姆  这个夏天有夏洛特在你开心吗
Have you enjoyed having Charlotte here all summer, Tim?
八月要结束了
There goes August.
我都教了他好多事情了
I've introduced him to most things, haven't I?
是的  你比他有经验嘛
You did. You were much more sophisticated.
而且不露声色
In a quiet way, I like to think.
进来
Come in.
夏洛特
Charlotte.
最后一晚了  能问你一个问题吗
As it's your last night, can I ask you a question?
问吧
Yeah. Ask away.
等等
No, wait.
不会是向我表白吧
It's not going to be about love, is it?
表白? 表白什么
Love? What?
奇巧警告过我
Well, it's just that Kit Kat warned me
如果你向我表白
that if you were to ever mention it,
那我就必须以强硬姿态告诉你
I should be very firm with you and tell you
必须把我当成你的妹妹
you must treat me like your sister
别做傻事
and not be stupid.
还是我完全误会了
Or have I just made a total fool of myself
你其实只是趁最后一晚
and you were actually going to ask me for
跑来问我关于打网球的技巧是吧
late night last minute tennis tips?
不是  我就是来表白的
No, it was the love thing.
好吧
Well.
你人真好
That's very sweet of you.
可惜你拖到最后一晚才表白
It's just a shame you left it till the last night.
你应该在我们还有时间的时候
You should have tried creeping along the corridor
多多溜到我门外来
while we still had time.
所以不该最后一晚表白?
Okay, the "Last night" was a bad idea?
是的
Very bad idea.
都快分开了才说  感觉有点侮辱人呢
It feels like an ever so slightly insulting afterthought.
最后一晚表白是行不通的
"Last night" was never going to work.
好的  就这样  我明白了
All right. Good. I've got it.
进来
Come in.
-蒂姆  -夏洛特
- Tim. - Charlotte.
坐这儿
Sit down.
可能你已经感觉到了
I know you've probably suspected this,
过去一个月我完完全全地爱上了你
but over the last month I've fallen completely in love with you.
现在是时候表白了
Now obviously this was gonna happen
你是我的女神  天使般的脸蛋
because you're a goddess with that face
一头柔软的长发
and that hair,
即使你没有漂亮的脸蛋
but even if you didn't have a nice face,
或是因为什么医疗事故
and even if you had absolutely no hair
你变成了秃子
because of some bizarre medical reason,
我依然喜欢你
I'd still adore you,
我...
and I...
我想知道我是否有一丝希望
I just wondered whether, by any chance,
让你也如此动心
you might share my feelings.
不如这样
I tell you what.
不如等到夏天结束
Why don't we see how the summer goes
到最后一晚再来表白
and then you ask me again on my last night?
-最后一晚? -是的
- Your last night? - Yes.
最后一晚再表白  或许会发生些奇迹哦
Try me on the last night. See what happens then, shall we?
我好期待呢
It's exciting.
对
Right.
不  是个完美计划
No, it's a perfect plan.
非常完美  最后一晚再表白
That's absolutely perfect. Last night.
最后一晚
Last night.
谢谢
Thanks very much.
晚安  蒂米
Night-night, Timmy.
经验教训第一条
Big lesson number one,
不管怎样穿越都也无法让人爱上你
all the time travel in the world can't make someone love you.
再见
Bye!
我的挚爱就这样离开我了
So the love of my life just drove away.
她走后第二天我也要走了
And the very next day it was my turn to leave.
拿着  别一次花完
There you go. Don't spend it all at once.
谢了
Thanks.
别老给家里打电话
Don't call too often,
你妈不喜欢老被人打扰
your mother doesn't like to be disturbed.
好的  知道了
Okay. Thanks.
我坐着火车来到了伦敦
I caught the train to London
寻找未来  和我的爱情
in search of a future and a girlfriend.
我住在我爸的剧作家朋友哈利家里
I was staying in St John's Wood, near Abbey Road,
他家在艾比路附近的圣约翰伍德区
with a playwright friend of my dad's called Harry.
初到伦敦  能有亲友们投靠
It's always nice to have family connections
真是一件好事
when you're a new kid in town.
你  他妈  想干嘛
What the fuck do you want?
我是詹姆斯的儿子
I'm James's son.
谁啊
Who?
-詹姆斯·莱克  -他怎么了
- James Lake. - What about him?
他说你有一间空房
He said you had a room.
进去  进到这  别动
Go in there and wait.
安静点  别弄出任何声响
Quietly. I mean it, don't make a sound.
不然我就杀了你
Or I'll kill you.
我刚想到了一个十年来最好的点子
I was actually having the first good idea I've had for a decade
你却按响了门铃
when you rang on the doorbell.
好了  现在全没了
But now it's gone.
你个小杂种
You little shit.
你老爸过得怎样
How's your dad?
我总觉得他是另类  有点怪怪的
Weird cock, I always thought. Something weird about him.
是吗
Really?
当然  其实我不太喜欢他
Yeah, I never really liked him, actually.
20世纪艺术界最有名的人物之一  波普艺术的倡导者和领袖
你妈现在长得还像安迪·沃霍尔吗
Your mum still look like Andy Warhol?
什么啊
What?
对了  那是我老婆
That, by the way, is my wife.
她很漂亮
Nice.
你一开始肯定不会喜欢她的
Yeah, you wouldn't like her at first.
牙尖嘴利的
Sarcastic cow.
但最终你会发现
But eventually you'd realise that
她是这世上最好的人
she's the best human being in the world.
理所当然  她离开我了
Which is why she left me, of course.
这是你的房间
Here you go.
不要搞太大声  尤其是在滚床单的时候
Try not to make too much noise, particularly when having sex.
那不可能的
No chance of that.
天啊  两个屌丝住在一个房子里
Christ, two losers in one house.
那是我女儿
That is my daughter.
喜欢就睡她吧  反正人人都睡过她
Have sex with her if you like. Apparently everyone else has.
住在这种地方很难有桃花
It wasn't a hopeful set-up for romance.
工作上也没什么机会
And work didn't help on that score either.
法律界就是个男人的世界
The world of law seems to be entirely full of men.
我是罗利  荣幸荣幸  有点小激动
I'm Rory. Very pleased to meet you. A real thrill.
咱俩说不定会成为哥们  是吧
Well, who knows, we might become, you know, pals, et cetera.
-你谁啊  -蒂姆·莱克
- Who the hell are you? - Tim Lake.
希望你别和这蠢瓜一样蠢就好
Well, I hope you're better than this clown.
快过来  罗杰
Come on, Roger.
是罗利啦
It's Rory, actually.
我都来这一年半了
I've been here a year and a half.
这是客气的说法
I'm just saying that to be nice.
我来这其实已经2年了
It's two years actually.
半年寂寞地度过了
So six lonely months went by,
仍只有我跟哈利作伴
and it was still just me and Harry.
我日以继夜地忙着工作
Me lawyer-ing every hour of the day and night.
他则为新的演出作最后准备
And him putting the finishing touches to his new play.
无论有多少女孩与我擦肩而过
No matter how many girls there were in the world,
最终却只有罗利会停留
I always seemed to end up with Rory.
你好
Hello.
直到突然有一晚
Until, out of the blue,
在跟不靠谱的杰出去玩时
on a dodgy night out with dodgy Jay,
奇迹发生了
something miraculous happened.
这些侍应
The waiters are,
没错  都是盲人
wait for this, right, they're blind.
开什么玩笑
You're kidding me?
我没开玩笑  他们真的是完全看不见
I'm kidding you not. No, as bats. As bats!
先生  欢迎光临
Very good to have you here, gentlemen.
希望你们用餐愉快
I hope you enjoy your experience.
卡罗会带你们进去
Carlo will show you to your table.
-好的  -走吧  大师
- Great. - Lead on, maestro.
把你的右手搭到我的右肩上吧
Can I have your right hand on my right shoulder, please?
你朋友搭在你肩上  多谢合作
And your friend hold on to your shoulder. Thank you.
小心楼梯  做好心理准备
Mind the stairs and be prepared because,
里边真的什么都看不见
it's completely dark.
好的  先生  要是不介意的话
Okay, gentlemen, if you don't mind,
你们可以坐在这两位女士的旁边
I can sit you here beside these two young ladies.
当然不介意  好极了
No, no. Sounds absolutely perfect!
天啊  听起来还挺自信
God, you sound very perky.
确实  而且还十分英俊
I am. And very handsome.
这边有人啊
Someone's there.
-你好  -你好  我叫玛丽
- Hi. - Hi. I'm Mary.
我叫蒂姆  其实我妈也叫玛丽
I'm Tim. Mary's my mother's name, actually.
-人如其名吗  -还凑合
- Does it suit her? - Sort of.
不过她身子硬朗
Although she's sturdy,
也许叫伯纳德[男名]更合适
so Bernard might have been a better fit.
好吧
Okay.
有东西碰到我手肘了
Something just touched my elbow.
放心  不是我
Okay, that wasn't me.
那更糟糕  要不是你  那是什么
No. Well, that just makes it worse. If it wasn't you, who was it?
也不是我  因为我在摸其他东西
It wasn't me because I'm touching something else.
是啊  把手拿开  谢谢
Yes, and you'll stop that right away, thank you.
说实话  你们俩谁更漂亮
So, girls, be honest, who is more beautiful?
-当然是我  -没错  是她
- I am. - Yeah. She is.
太棒了
Excellent!
其实我长得像凯特·摩斯
Actually, I look like Kate Moss.
凯特·摩斯  一位争议较多的世界级超模
真的吗
Really?
假的  我看起来像只松鼠
No. I sort of look like a squirrel.
你喜欢凯特·摩斯吗
Do you like Kate Moss?
我爱死她了
I absolutely love her.
其实今晚我打算
In fact, I almost wore
穿一条她的裙子  你呢
one of her dresses here tonight. You?
我没有  她的衣服不适合我
No, no, her clothes look terrible on me.
真不敢相信你也下周生日
I cannot believe that it's your birthday next week as well.
你的朋友有够热情的
Your friend Jay is quite enthusiastic.
其实我挺讨厌他
I actually hate him.
乔安娜这人怎样
What's Joanna like?
-基本上就是个妓女  -是啊
- She's basically a prostitute. - Yeah.
我猜这是草莓慕斯
I think it's strawberry mousse.
要尝尝吗
Do you want some?
好的  让我尝尝
Okay. I'll try it.
好的  你的嘴在哪儿
Okay, where's your mouth?
在...
It's...
在这儿
It's here.
好的  是这吗
Okay. There?
老天  碰到哪儿了
My God, what was that?
那是我的眼睛
That's my eye.
我的眼...
I think there's a lot of...
现在我眼里都是草莓慕斯了
I've got quite a lot of strawberry mousse in my eye now!
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
没事  还要谢谢你帮我找到种新吃法
No. Thank you. That's a new sensation for me.
或许我们在外面见见面
So, maybe I'll see you outside or...
好啊  很好
Yeah. Yeah, great.
好的  有点害怕
Great. Scary.
是啊  是有点害怕
Yeah, it's a bit scary.
天啊  我很享受  你呢
My God, I'm so in there. What about you?
不知道  不过听上去很不错
I don't know, but she sounded wonderful.
-乔安娜  -杰
- Joanna? - Jay.
老天  可真是个尤物
Christ, you're a babe.
有兴趣下半场吗
How do you fancy stretching the night out a bit?
我可以打发走他
I can ditch the loser.
我们赶时间  不过帮我拦出租车的话
We've got to rush, but help me find a cab,
我会考虑给你号码
and I might give you my number.
当然没问题
Of course. Yeah.
也可能不给  不过我还没决定
Or I might not. Haven't decided yet. So...
我才不会把号码给他
I have. it's not gonna happen.
-你好  -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
-她在哪  -她跟杰...
- Where's... - She and Jay just...
她跟他去了...我不知道
She took him to... I don't know.
好吧
Right.
我还是...
Well, I guess I'd better...
要是我问你要号码会不会太唐突了
Would it be very wrong if I asked you for your number?
不会
No.
以防我找你...
Just in case I ever had to call you about...
有事?
Stuff?
好吧
Okay.
方不方便...
Would you...
我叫玛丽
It's Mary.
玛丽
Mary.
好了
Okay.
我以前觉得这台手机又破又旧
I thought this phone was old and shit,
不过现在它成了我最珍贵的东西了
but suddenly it's my most valuable possession.
你真的喜欢我吗
You really like me?
即使我穿的连衣裙
Even my frock?
我喜欢你的连衣裙
I love your frock.
我的头发呢  是不是太棕了
And my hair? It's not too brown?
我爱棕色
I love brown.
我刘海是新剪的
My fringe is new.
刘海很完美  简直是点睛之笔
The fringe is perfect. Fringe is the best bit.
玛丽
Mary!
该走了
We have to go!
再不走他那不靠谱的朋友就要侵犯我了
I found a cab and his dodgy friend is about to assault me.
好的  马上到
Okay, I'm coming.
再两秒钟
Two seconds.
我希望能再见到你
I hope I see you again.
你会的
You will.
好的  很好
Okay. Good.
晚安
Goodnight.
发生什么事
What's happened?
你干嘛了  可怜的家伙
What have you done, you poor thing?
没什么  只不过多了道新伤口
Nothing. It's just a flesh wound.
-给  -谢谢
- Here. - Thank you.
你也知道我的戏今晚上演
You may remember, my play opened tonight.
老天  对啊  怎样了
My God, yes. How did it go?
进展顺利
Well. it went well.
可以说杰作得以面世
You could tell in the room a masterpiece was being unfurled.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Really.
直到演至全剧最关键的转折点
Until, and this is the crucial plot point, I think,
主角出现有史以来
until the lead actor had the most massive dry
最严重的忘词状况
in the history of theatre.
-不会吧  -是的  就是这样
- No, no, no. - Yes, yes, yes.
这不仅仅是他忘词的问题
He didn't just forget his lines.
他忘词忘得严重到
He forgot his lines to the extent
戏剧艺术史册上的一切忘词
that no actor has ever forgotten their lines
都显得不值一提
before in the annals of dramatic art.
评论也不会说"伟大杰作得以面世"
The reviews won't say "Major masterpiece gets unveiled",
而只会说"主角得了老年痴呆症"
they'll say, "Major actor gets Alzheimer's."
简直是场灾难
It's a disaster.
这样讲还是太轻描淡写了
It's an understatement.
这是有《泰坦尼克号》的精彩开头
It's the Titanic of play openings,
却无人幸存的悲剧收尾
but with no survivors.
没女人  没小孩
No women, no children,
连凯特·温丝莱特也没活下来
not even Kate Winslet.
凯特·温丝莱特  《泰坦尼克号》女主角  在电影结尾活了下来
全死光了
All dead.
好吧  我看看能做点什么
Okay. I'll see what I can do.
你这话什么意思
What does that mean?
你打算怎么做
What are you gonna do?
给在伦敦的每位评论家打电话
Ring up every critic in London,
为他们口交  以此来让他们忽略
and offer them a blow job, if they ignore the fact
观众在一片安静中干坐半个小时
that we sat in total silence for half an hour
只为等个白痴记起句台词这个事实吗
waiting for a moron to remember one single line?
并不是
Not quite that.
哈利·查普曼作品  《罪人》
你好
Hello.
你好  汤姆先生  我是哈利的朋友
Hello, Sir Tom. I'm a friend of Harry's.
请问你台词记得怎样了
How's it going with the lines?
抱歉  什么叫台词记得怎样
I'm sorry, what do you mean "the lines"?
就是在法庭场景上
It's just, you know, in the court scenes,
有些台词是比较复杂的
some of those lines are pretty complex.
所以我就想提醒你一下
And I just thought maybe it might be worth, you know,
上台前再看一眼台词
having one last look at the lines before you go on.
算是重温一下
A little refresher.
快滚出去
Fuck off out of here.
你这个疯子  快滚  蠢货  滚
You arsing lunatic. Get out! You ginger twerp. Go on!
保护这种...
Patronising piece of...
请辩方发言
And now the Defence.
我也是从失公允的年代中走来的
I have lived many weary years.
太棒了
It's brilliant.
即便在冗长的法律诉讼史中
But never, in that long catalogue of wasted time,
也未曾遇到过如此罪恶的审判不公
have I ever seen such an atrocious miscarriage of justice.
控诉方还要作何补充
Do the Prosecution have anything final to add?
抱歉  借过一下
Sorry, excuse me. Sorry.
控诉方还要作何补充
Do the Prosecution have anything final to add?
各位...
Gentlemen...
各位
Gentlemen,
对今日的诉讼我一直秉承最认真的态度
I regard today's proceedings with the utmost gravity.
然而
Nevertheless,
有一点虽简单
let us be clear of one
但却不容忽视
simple and salient thing.
那就是
It is the life
罪人的生命权
of a guilty man!
我看有个演员像是睡着了一样
One of the actors appeared to have actually fallen asleep.
中途离场的小混蛋过来了
Here's the little prick who walked out halfway through.
你错过了最精彩的一幕  蠢货
You missed the best scene, you little twerp.
抱歉
Sorry.
你觉得布景怎样
What did you think of the set?
太不可思议了
I thought it was incredible.
真的吗  我倒不觉得  太棕了
Did you? I didn't. Too brown.
玛丽
Mary!
不会吧
No.
她消失了
She's gone.
今晚有没有看到过两个女孩
Two girls in earlier tonight.
其中一个是这世上最漂亮的女孩
One of them the prettiest girl in the world.
另一个有点像稍有姿色的妓女
The other one like a sort of nice prostitute.
有登记她们的名字吗
Did you get their names?
是的  她们刚走不久  等我找找
Yes. They left a while ago. Let's see.
她们不是预订的  所以没有留下名字
No, I'm afraid they were walk-ins,
而且是用现金结的账
and it appears they paid by cash.
抱歉  先生
Sorry, sir.
没事  没事  很好
That's okay. That's fine, it's brilliant.
只不过是我的世界末日罢了  谢谢了
It's just the end of my life. Thanks so much.
开心点  伙计
Cheer up, mate.
要知道你现在
Apparently, you're living with
是跟英国最伟大的在世剧作家住一块
Britain's greatest living playwright.
通常我都不看他们写的东西
I don't usually read them, obviously,
不过这是例外
but I couldn't resist this one.
《哈利·查普曼天资过高  被判有罪》
"Harry Chapman found guilty of genius."
凯特·摩斯摄影作品展
我要走了  现在就走
I have to go out. Right now.
为什么
Why?
她爱凯特·摩斯
She loves Kate Moss.
马里奥·泰斯蒂诺《谁是凯特》摄影展
谢谢你来陪我  小凯
Thanks for keeping me company, Kittle.
反正也没事做
Nothing better to do.
吉米呢
How's Jimmy?
又把我甩了
Dumped me.
又来了
Not again.
-工作呢  -炒我鱿鱼了
- And work? - They've sacked me.
他们真白痴
Idiots.
-喝咖啡吗  -谢谢
- Coffee? - Please.
我只注意到照片中的猫  看到没
I've only just noticed this cat in this picture. See that cat?
看到了  真不错
I do see that cat. It's very good.
老天
My God.
My God!
干嘛
What?
就是她
It's her.
It's her!
就是她
That's her!
去吧  小伙子
You go, girl.
抱歉
Sorry.
-你好  -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
你好吗
How are you?
我...我很好
I'm... I'm fine.
见到你真好
It's so good to see you.
我们素未谋面
We've never met before.
不  他妈的
No, fuck.
-是啊  我们没见过  -没见过
- No, of course we haven't. - No.
抱歉  我想你认错人了
Sorry, I think you've mistaken me for someone else.
不  不  不是
No, no, no.
你的名字叫玛丽
Your name's Mary.
真是奇怪了
That's distinctly weird.
你是怎么知道的
How do you know that?
因为你长得像玛丽
Well, you look like a Mary.
怎么说
In what way?
我妈也叫玛丽
My mum's called Mary.
我长得像你妈吗
I look like your mother?
不像  你比她漂亮多了
No. You're much prettier.
顺便提一下  刘海不错
It's a nice fringe, by the way.
老天  我新剪的  可能太短了
God, it's new and probably too short but... No.
谢谢你的夸奖
Well, gee, thank you and...
很高兴见到你
listen, it was really nice to meet you.
不过我要走了  我朋友在等我呢
I should probably go because my friend's waiting for me.
况且咱们根本不认识
And you're a, you're a total stranger.
根本不认识
Total stranger.
是啊  这也太疯狂了
Yeah, it's crazy stuff.
-是有点  -好吧
- Yeah, kind of. - Okay.
-再见  玛丽  -再见
- Bye, Mary. - Bye.
不
No.
怎么样了
How did it go?
太惨了
It was very poor.
真的十分惨
Very poor indeed, yeah.
那就再来一次
You gotta go again.
-你可以的  -再来一次
- You can do it. - Take two.
她总是...总是那么的与众不同
She just always... She always looks different.
抱歉  又是我
Sorry. it's me again.
-你好  -抱歉
- Hi. - Sorry.
乔安娜  他是...
Joanna, this is...
蒂姆
Tim.
你好  很高兴见到你
Hello. Nice to meet you.
蒂姆是碰巧妈妈跟我同名的陌生人
Tim is a total stranger whose mother's name is Mary.
我在这把玛丽认作是其他人了
I just had a weird experience with Mary here
但其实她不是
of thinking she was someone else. But she wasn't.
不过我想能不能和你们一起参观
But I just wondered if I could walk round with you for a while,
因为我妹妹要走了
because my sister Kit Kat is about to leave.
是啊
Yeah.
再见
Bye.
所以
And so,
就剩下我一个人  挺孤单的
I'm about to be quite lonely.
好吧  我们的回答是不可以
Right. Well, I think we should probably say no.
可以啊  他笑起来挺可爱的
No, yes. But on the other hand, he's got a quite nice smile,
头发也挺搞笑
and sort of, you know, fun hair.
可以啊
Yeah.
好吧
All right.
不过你得保证
But you have to promise that
你不是以下的其中之一
you are not one of the following things.
第一  疯子
One, a lunatic.
-没错  -我不是
- Yeah. - No.
第二  恋刘海癖
Two, a fringe fetishist.
我只是凯特·摩斯的头号男粉丝
I'm just Kate Moss's number one male fan.
-老天  -真的吗
- God. - Really?
是啊  肯定是啊
Yeah. God, yeah.
你觉不觉得她的魅力来自于她的过去
Do you agree that the magic of her lies in her history?
看她早期打破常规的作品
That the informality of her early shots
与现如今的相比  你就知道
compared to this stuff so you just always know,
即便身穿高级时装
That despite the high fashion,
她依旧是那个在海滩上坦然全裸的不羁女孩
she's still just that cheeky normal naked girl on the beach?
说的太好了
Couldn't have put it better myself.
一语中的  我深表认同
That's absolutely it. I agree with that profoundly.
要牛奶吗
Milk?
要
Yes.
-糖呢  -不要
- Sugar? - No.
男朋友呢
Boyfriend?
有了
Yes!
不  不  你没有男朋友
No. No, you don't have a boyfriend.
我看上去不像有男朋友吗
Do I not look like I'd have a boyfriend?
-我看上去像交不到男朋友吗  -不像
- Do I look like I'd never get a boyfriend? - No.
这是我听过最无礼的话
That's the rudest thing I've ever heard.
我不是这个意思  我只是没想到...
I didn't mean it like that. I just didn't expect...
是新交的男朋友吗
Is it quite a new boyfriend?
是的
Yes.
就是他  鲁伯特
There he is. Rupert.
-是啊  他很可爱  -鲁伯特
- Yes. He's so cute. - Rupert?
大家好
Hi, guys.
抱歉我来晚了  跟我爸来的
Sorry I'm late, with my dad.
你好  鲁比
Hi, Rupee.
鲁比?
"Rupee"?
这是蒂姆
Well, this is Tim and
我们并不认识他
we don't know him at all.
我觉得我们过后可以看场电影
Hey, I was thinking we could take in a film after this.
来桶爆米花  一杯可乐两个人喝
Get some mixed popcorn, share a Coke,
-靠在一起  -好啊
- snuggle. - Okay.
好
Okay.
你们什么时候认识的  什么时间点
When did you two meet? Exactly?
其实就是一周前
Well, it was only a week ago, actually.
真是快如闪电啊  是不是  乖乖狗
It's all been a bit of a whirlwind, hasn't it, poochy face?
我得教教你
I'm gonna have to teach you
在别人面前什么能说  什么不能说
what you can and can't say in front of people.
-"乖乖狗"不能说吗  -不行
- No "foochy face"? - No.
不  当然不行
No. Definitely not.
来来  再说说你们美妙的初次见面
Come on, then. More details about this wonderful first meeting?
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
那天是几号来着  乔安娜
It was, um, what... Joanna?
6月17日
June 17th.
对  乔开了一个小型派对
Yeah. And Jo was having a little party.
简直是个炼狱  幸好鲁伯特救了我
A living hell from which Rupert, thank God, rescued me.
这个糟糕的派对在哪儿呢
And where was this terrible party?
就在我的破公寓里
My brothel of a flat.
那是在哪儿呢  重点就在这  不是吗
Which is where, though? That's the question, isn't it?
怎么  你是侦探吗
What are you, a detective?
不是  抱歉  我喜欢把想象视觉化
No, sorry, I've just got a very visual imagination.
把一切细节都想象到
I like to imagine stuff completely.
西南五区  科菲尔德花园26号
26 Courtfield Gardens, SW5.
八点半左右
Around 8:30.
着装要求  火辣  这样行了吧
Dress code, slutty. Will that do?
当然  很好  不过我还想知道
Absolutely, yes. Although I am wondering
你是什么时候到的  是早是晚  鲁伯特
when you got there, Rupert. Early, late?
准时到吧  真爱在召唤呢
On time, I think. True love was calling.
老天
God.
我感觉有些不舒服
I actually feel a bit sick now.
可能是这些松饼  千万别吃蓝莓的
Just these muffins, I think. Never trust a blueberry.
好的  我马上回来
Okay, I'll be back in a tick.
你们俩真的很般配
You two are such a lovely couple.
有点怪
Bit weird.
挺可爱的
He's cute.
我喜欢他
I like him.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
厕所
楼梯
你好  我们认识吗
Hello. Do I know you?
不不  我是玛丽的朋友
No, no, no. I'm a friend of Mary's.
她又有个朋友
She has another friend?
天哪  你真惊人  棒极了
Gosh, you amaze me. But hooray.
来个热狗吗
Ooh. Hotdog?
我自己做的  花了几小时呢
Took me hours. Made them myself.
谢谢
Thanks.
难吃死了  完全没熟
Disgusting. Totally undercooked.
回头见
See you later.
我们上楼去吧  上面安静些
Why don't we go upstairs, it's a bit quieter?
我叫蒂姆
I'm Tim.
我叫玛丽
Mary.
和我妈妈一样  不过不说这个了
That's my mother's name. Let's not get into that.
我知道这样很唐突  但是
I know this is forward but
你的表情告诉我
your face tells me that
你觉得这派对是个人间炼狱
you're finding this party to be a living hell.
所以我想问你  是不是愿意
So, I just wondered if you might come
和我一起出去吃点东西
and have a bite to eat with me instead?
就现在
Right now.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
好吧  我该再想清楚些的
Obviously, I should have thought this through more.
我们聊聊凯特·摩斯吧
Let's talk about Kate Moss.
我很喜欢凯特·摩斯
I love Kate Moss.
我一直觉得  她的过去才是关键
I always think the key thing with her is the history,
-没错  -她早期打破常规的作品
- Yes. - you know, the informality of her early shots
和高级时装摄影形成对比
compared to high fashion stuff
你会知道  她的内心从未改变  还是那个
so you always know that underneath she's still just the same
在海滩上坦然全裸的不羁女孩
cheeky normal girl naked on the beach.
沙滩
The beach.
我完全同意
I agree with you completely.
如果我们现在就走
If we leave now then we can have,
就可以多吃几道开胃菜了
you know, more than one starter.
你的眼睛真美
I love your eyes.
你脸上的其他部分也是
And I love the rest of your face, too.
多吃几道开胃菜
More than one starter?
十道绝妙的开胃菜
10 amazing starters.
-你先  -谢谢
- After you. - Thanks.
不管什么派对  待上十分钟都够长的了
Ten minutes is long enough for any party, I think.
是啊
Yeah.
特别是这个
Especially that one.
晚上好啊
Evening, all.
天哪  真是个蠢蛋
God! What a dickhead.
就是
Yeah.
你是做什么的
So, what do you do?
我在出版社看书
I'm a reader at a publisher.
不是吧  你看书也能赚钱
No! You read for a living?
没错  我的工作就是看书
Yes, that's it. I read.
有这么好的事
That's so great.
就好像有人问你  "你靠什么过活"
It's like someone asking, "What do you do for a living?"
"我呼吸就好了  有人花钱让我呼吸"
"Well, I breathe. I'm a breather, I get paid for breathing."
-你怎么找到这工作的  -好了机灵鬼
- How did you get that job? - Okay, smart-ass,
你是做什么的
what do you do?
我是个律师
I am a lawyer.
差不多是吧
Sort of. Sort of.
真带感
That's sexy.
是吗
Is it?
我是这么觉得的
I mean, I think so.
穿着律师袍在法庭上拯救别人的生活
In a suit, in a court, saving people's lives.
是挺带感的
Kinda sexy.
我想也是  不过肯定没有看书带感
I guess it is. Although it's not as sexy as reading.
在办公室里  坐在一张椅子上看书
Sitting there in an office, in a little chair reading.
好了  打住  打住
Okay, stop. Stop.
没这么简单  听我说
Just wait right there, mister, because
交给我们出版社的书有很多
a lot of books get submitted to my publisher.
所以这是个很大的责任
So it's an immense responsibility.
肯定是
I bet it is.
那你正常阅读的时候
But when you do normal reading,
会不会被工作影响呢
is it ruined because it's your job?
就像妓女
You know, like prostitutes?
我总是担心  当她们不再干那一行
I always worry that when they stop being prostitutes
她们就不能享受做爱的感觉了
that they can't enjoy sex any more.
你总是担心这个吗
You always worry about that?
-不  有时候会担心  -好吧
- No, I sometimes worry about it. - Good. Okay.
总是担心这个的人
Because someone who always worried about that
-可不太让人放心  -你读报纸的时候
- would be a bit of a worry. - When you read a newspaper,
会不会想  "算了  这是工作"
do you think, "Forget this, it's work"?
你是不是见过很多妓女
Have you interviewed a lot of prostitutes?
你看菜单的时候  是不是也会想
When you read a menu, do you think,
"我才不看呢  除非你付我现金"
"No, I'm not reading this, unless you pay me hard cash."
你得和多少个妓女谈过
How many prostitutes will you need to talk to
才能解决这个问题呢
before this issue is solved?
你有没想过去东欧和泰国呢
Are you planning to head to Eastern Europe and Thailand?
陪我走到车那儿去  好吗
Would you like to walk me to my car?
-好啊  -好的
- Yes. - Okay.
当然好
Why not?
这主意不错
Sounds like a good idea.
那你呢
What about you?
我有三个哥哥
Yeah, I have three older brothers.
-天哪  -是啊
- God. - Yeah.
他们在哪
Where are they?
在你背后
Behind you.
你是没地方停车吗
Did you have trouble parking?
什么
Pardon?
停在这么远的地方
It's just such a long way to your car.
其实  我的车就停在我家外面
Well, my car's actually parked outside my house.
我是搭便车去的派对
I got a lift to the party.
好吧
Okay.
很好  太好了
That's good. That's perfect.
是吗
Okay.
到了
And here we are.
我的天
My God.
车子  家  家  车子
Car, house. House, car.
原来如此
It makes perfect sense.
很合逻辑
It's very logical.
老天爷
Christ.
钥匙
Keys!
我去房间换上新睡衣
I'm gonna go into the bedroom and put on my new pyjamas.
好的
Right.
一分钟后  你可以进来帮我脱掉
And then in a minute you can come in and take them off.
如果你愿意的话
If you want to.
一分钟
One minute.
-天啊  你...没事吧  -没事
- God. Are you... Are you okay? - Yeah.
抱歉
Sorry.
没关系
That's okay.
这是前扣式的
It's a front opener.
这是什么
It's a what?
扣子在前面
It opens from the front.
原来如此
Yeah, no, yeah, of course.
-谢了  -没事
- Thanks. - Sure.
真棒
Ooh! Well done.
下次肯定会更好
I'm sure it'll be better next time.
我觉得已经很好了
I thought it was pretty lovely.
是啊  确实很好
Right, no, it was really lovely.
你等我一下好吗
In fact, can you just give me one minute?
好的
Okay.
真危险
Dangerous.
你还真懂内衣啊
You really know your bras.
希望如此
I like to think so.
真不错  有些人第一次搞得一团糟
Well done. Some people make a real mess of it the first time.
菜鸟吧
Amateurs.
等我一下好吗
Could you give me one second?
当然
Sure.
我等不及了
I couldn't wait.
我的老天
My goodness.
我这辈子最好的一夜
Best night of my entire life.
接下来  我猜我要
And now I've got a suspicion
睡上这辈子最好的一觉了
I'm gonna have the best sleep of my entire life.
我的完美男人  一次就够了吗
So once is enough for my perfect guy?
这么说可不太公平
I'm not sure that's entirely fair.
-迟到了  -没有
- We're late. - No, we're not.
没事的  现在才...天哪
It'll be fine. It's only... My God.
The Waterboys: How Long Will I Love You?
我会爱你多久
How long will I love you?
只要星星在空中
As long as stars are above you
再见
Bye.
甚至可以更长久
And longer if I can
我会需要你多久
How long will I need you?
别担心  没问题的
Don't worry, you're coming with.
只要四季
As long as the seasons need to
我带你回家
I'm taking you home!
轮换依旧
Follow their plan
我会给你多少时间
How long will I give to you
-再见  -再见
- Bye. Bye. - Bye.
只要我们在一起
As long as I live to you
不
No!
多久都没有问题
However long you say
我会爱你多久
How long will I love you?
只要星星在空中
As long as stars are above you
甚至可以更长久
And longer if I may
我有个坏消息
Okay. I have some bad news.
-你要死了吗  -不  没那么糟
- You're dying? - No, not that bad.
-我要死了  -不是
- I'm dying? - No.
我父母进城来了
My parents are in town.
他们要过来  就快到了
They're visiting and they're coming around.
天哪  父母  美国的父母吗
God. Parents? American parents?
-什么时候  -现在
- When? - Now.
他们事先和我说了  我没告诉你
They told me and I didn't tell you
我以为他们会临时取消
and I thought they'd cancel
因为他们经常这样  但这次没有
because they normally do and they didn't.
-就这会儿吗  -就这会儿
- Now now? - Now now.
所以你最好穿条裤子
So you should probably put on some pants.
老天  好  好
God. Okay, okay.
抱歉  都怪我
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
他们知道我这个人吗
Do they know I exist?
知道  我稍微提过
Yeah. I've mentioned something like you,
但没说得很具体
but nothing very specific.
对了  他们比较保守  还是换条裤子吧
Yeah, they're quite conservative, so maybe not those pants.
好的  好的
Okay. Yeah.
天哪  好吧
God. Okay.
你能先拖住他们吗  拖一会儿
Could you just stall them. Stall them.
上来吧
Come on up.
-什么  -抱歉了  他们不喜欢等
- What? - I'm sorry, they don't like waiting.
-好吧  -我要说我住这儿吗
- Okay. - Do I live here?
绝对不行
Definitely not.
那能说我们做爱吗
Are we having sex?
可以  但别说口交
Yeah. But not oral.
我没打算说这个
I wasn't gonna mention oral.
很好  别说
Okay, good, don't.
你为什么觉得会说到这个
How did you think that was gonna come up?
能帮我弄一下这个吗
Could you help me with this, please?
不知道  如果说到了  就一口否认
I don't know. If it does, just deny it completely.
谁会问到这个  你爸爸吗
Who's gonna bring it up? Your dad?
"蒂姆  最近跟我女儿口交了吗"
"Tim, had any cunnilingus with my daughter recently?"
这可不好说
Well, you never know.
好吧
Okay.
-好  准备好了吗  -好了
- Okay. Ready? - Yeah.
-他们到了  -到了
- They're there. - They are, yeah.
-我就在你背后  -好的  好的
- Yeah, right behind you. - Okay. Right, okay.
-爸爸  -好啊  宝贝
- Dad! - Hello, sweet.
-妈妈  -好啊  亲爱的
- Mom. - Hi, honey.
这是蒂姆
This is Tim.
先生  太太  你们好
Hello, sir. Ma'am.
我们要不要等你朋友走了再来  还是...
Should we come back when you haven't got any company, or...
那不太可能
Well, that would be quite difficult
因为蒂姆就住在这儿
because Tim actually lives here.
是吗  和你一起住
Really? With you?
是的  但是没有口交  我保证
Yes. Yeah, but no oral sex, I promise you.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
失陪一下
Excuse me.
蒂姆  说说你是哪里人  哪个地方的
So, Tim, tell us where are you from, which part of the country?
他是康沃尔的  那儿很漂亮
He's from Cornwall. Yeah, it's really pretty.
就是西南端鞋子形状的那块地方
It's that little bit right at the end, sort of looks like a shoe.
你是个律师  对吗
And you're a lawyer, is that right?
是的  没错  他从没输过
Yep, that's right. And he never loses.
有时候你以为他肯定赢不了了
You don't think he's gonna win,
但他总能想出个妙招
then he just pulls something out of the bag and,
然后就赢了
what do you know, he wins again.
你会自己回答问题吗
Do you ever answer any of your own questions?
-我...-他会的  他一般都自己回答
- I... - Yes, he does. Usually he does,
但今天不行  因为我一直说个不停
but not today because I'm doing all the talking
因为我很紧张
because I'm really nervous
我太喜欢他了  我希望你们也能喜欢他
and I kinda love him and I just... I want you to, too.
宝贝
Honey.
抱歉  蒂姆  你自己来吧
Sorry. Tim. Over to you.
说吧
Shoot.
-我想我爸爸...-我再说一句好吗
- Yeah, I think my dad... - Can I just say one more thing?
好
Yep.
谢天谢地  终于结束了
Thank God that's over.
我拿到两张国家剧院的票  明天的
I got given two tickets for the National Theatre tomorrow.
一起去吗
Do you wanna come?
不去了  我要睡一整天
No, so not. I'm just gonna sleep all day.
我不明白了  去剧院对睡觉有影响吗
I don't see why going to the theatre should get in the way of that.
我最好的几次睡眠
Many of the best sleeps of my life
都是在皇家莎士比亚剧院
have happened in the Royal Shakespeare Company.
不了  你带别人一起去吧
No, you take someone else.
我喜欢窝床上  不喜欢剧院
I really like bed and I really hate theatre.
好吧
Quite right.
哪个可怜鬼会周六晚上没有活动
But what kind of sad act is gonna be free on a Saturday night
还随叫随到
with no day's notice?
太棒了
Bravo.
-天哪  是夏洛特  -谁
- My God. It's Charlotte. - Who?
-我的初恋  -在哪
- It was my first love. - Where?
那边  出口标志下面
There. Under the "Exit" sign.
-那个老女人吗  -不  不是那个老女人
- The old woman? - No, not the old woman.
那个金发美女
The astonishing blonde.
-黑头发的吗  -不是  金发的
- The one with the dark hair? - No, blonde.
金发就是金色的头发  听不明白吗
Blonde means blonde hair, doesn't it?
在台下
Off the stage.
好  你待在这别动  说真的  待着
Okay, you stay there. I mean it, stay!
夏洛特
Charlotte.
天哪  蒂姆
My God. Tim.
见到你真好
How fabulous to see you.
我...这是我的女朋友  蒂娜
Wow. I... This is my girlfriend Tina.
不是吧
No.
太棒了  你好  蒂娜
That is so brilliant. Well, hello, Tina.
什么太棒了
Why is it brilliant?
生命里总会有一些时刻
Well, you know, there are certain moments in your life
会留下永久的创伤
that scar you for life.
夏洛特对我的拒绝  就是这样
Charlotte's rejection of me was one of those moments,
不过现在我知道她有"女朋友"了
but now I know she's got a "girlfriend", well,
这就让我松了一大口气了
that's just a huge burden suddenly lifted off my mind.
我可以重新做个自信的异性恋了
I can be a confident heterosexual all over again.
不是那种女朋友
Not that kind of girlfriend.
什么
What?
你以为我是同性恋吗
You think I'm gay?
不是
No.
不  当然不是
No, of course not.
不  应该是女性朋友
No. It's girl friend.
是的  不是
Yes. No. Wow.
女性的朋友  就是这样
Yeah, friend who is a girl, which you so clearly are.
我得去找一下我的男朋友  是个男的...
I'm just gonna go and get my boyfriend, who is a boy...
我的天啊  蒂姆
My God. Tim.
见到你真好  看看你
How lovely to see you. Look at you. Wow.
这是我的女朋友  蒂娜
This is my girlfriend Tina.
你好  蒂娜
Hello, Tina.
不过  你最好注意下用词
Although you should be a little careful with that, by the way.
还是会有很多守旧的人
There are still quite a lot of us old fashioned types about
会把"女朋友"理解成"同性恋"
who interpret "girlfriend" as meaning "gay".
如果你说蒂娜是你女朋友
So if you say that Tina's your girlfriend,
别人就会以为你们是"同性恋"
people will assume that you're "gay".
我就是"同性恋"
I am "gay".
是吗
Are you?
你有意见吗
Do you have a problem with that?
不  不是  我可喜欢了
No, I don't. I love that stuff.
我去一下...
I'm just gonna...
我看见三年前那个夏天让我心碎的女孩了
I've just seen the girl who broke my heart three summers ago.
去打个招呼吧
Let's go say hello.
不  还是别找麻烦了  走吧
No. Best let sleeping dogs lie. Come on.
今晚真是妙极了  我很喜欢这里
Best night of my life. I always love this area.
很热闹  还有那些色彩艳丽的画
It's so bustling and I mean those pictures, full of colour.
每次来这里都很开心
Just makes me so happy when I'm round here,
-这么多色彩  -蒂姆
- all the colour... - Tim.
夏洛特
Charlotte!
蒂姆  见到你真好
Tim, how lovely to see you.
真是个惊喜啊
What a surprise.
抱歉  这是我的女朋友  蒂娜
Wow. Sorry. This is my girlfriend, Tina.
-她是同性恋  -闭嘴
- She's gay. - Shut up.
蒂娜
Hello, Tina.
瞧瞧你
Look at you!
我都没想到
It just never even occurred to me
能在康沃尔郡之外遇到你
you existed outside of Cornwall.
我们正要去吃饭
We're about to go and get dinner,
但有机会能一起出去就好了
but it would be great to hang out sometime.
当然好  非常愿意
Yeah, sure. I'd love that.
帮我跟奇巧带个好  她好吗
Send my love to little Kit Kat. How is she?
她还行  其实她在伦敦也过得不容易
She's okay. She's not finding London totally easy actually.
是啊  吉米说他有时候会见她
Right. Well, Jimmy says he sees her sometimes.
是吗  从什么时候开始的
Really? Since when?
你也知道  他俩一直纠缠不清
You knew there was always something there.
不好意思  你是
Sorry, you are?
我很好  谢谢
Very well, thank you.
她是问你的名字
Well, she means your name.
-罗杰  -不对
- Roger. - No, it's not.
不是罗杰  我叫罗利
No, it's not. it's Rory.
-很高兴认识你  罗利  -嗯
- Nice to meet you, Rory. - Yeah.
对了  对不起  我们该走了
Right. Sorry, we should get going.
真的很高兴见到你
It was really great to see you.
-我们再见吧  -再见
- I'll see you soon. - You, too. Yeah.
再见
Bye.
天哪  她真美
God, she is beautiful.
她太美了  要是你跟她上床你会死的
She's so beautiful, if you had sex with her, you'd die. You'd just die.
脱她的衣服  看她的胸眼睛都会爆炸
You'd open her shirt, see her breasts and your eyes would explode.
你就得瞎着跟她做爱  然后就死了
You'd have to have sex with her blind. And then you'd die.
注意到了吗  她没给我她的号码
You notice she didn't give me her number...
我让蒂娜自己去吃饭了  你饿吗
I told Tina to go have dinner on her own. Are you hungry?
-饿  当然饿  -太好了
- Yeah. Of course. - Great.
再见  罗杰
Bye, Roger.
好  太棒了
Yeah, excellent.
再次谢谢你带我来看表演  祝你凯旋
Thanks again for the play. Triumph.
你想去哪
Where do you wanna go?
你喜欢的就行
Well, wherever you like really.
我比不了
I can't compete.
知道吗
You know,
我开始有点觉得我们浪费了那个暑假
I'm starting to think we slightly wasted that summer holiday.
要是我们能穿越回去
If we could travel back in time,
也许我不会拒绝
maybe I wouldn't have said no.
我
I'm...
我就住在拐角
I'm just staying round the corner.
能送我上楼吗
Can you walk me home?
好
Yeah.
-可以吗  -当然可以
- Yeah? - Yeah, of course, yeah.
我们到了
Well, here we are.
里面
It's a lot nicer
更好
inside.
我觉得也是
I'm sure it is.
那...那么
So... So...
那
So...
So,
很高兴
lovely
见到你  夏洛特
to see you, Charlotte.
真是美好的夜晚  很开心
What a night. Total joy, but I've gotta
但我得回去了
get back
因为我有件很重要的事要做  立刻做
because there's something very important that I have to do. Right now.
-醒醒  醒醒  -什么
- Wake up. Wake up. - What?
玛丽
Mary.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Would you like to marry me?
别那么自私  我在睡觉呢  真差劲
Don't be so selfish, I'm sleeping. It's bad.
对
Right.
真顺利
That went very well.
醒醒
Wake up.
什么
What?
醒醒  来聊聊天
Wake up. Come and have a chat.
干什么
Why?
我有件很重要的事要问你
I've got something important to ask you.
不能等明早吗
Can't it wait till morning?
不行
Not really.
可是我好舒服
But I'm so comfy.
我正在做最美的梦
I was having the loveliest dream.
什么事
What is it?
为什么有音乐
Why is there music on?
跟我要问你的事有关
It's got something to do with what I want to ask you.
等一下
Wait a minute.
浪漫音乐
Romantic music.
有重要问题的男人
Guy with important question.
你跪下了吗
Are you on your knees?
跪着
On his knees.
你看表演看太无聊了  就决定
Were you so bored in the play you decided
结束后来跟我求婚吗
to ask me to marry you afterwards?
差不多
Something like that.
对  完全正确
Yeah. Exactly that.
说真的
In fact,
你愿意嫁给我吗
will you marry me?
有想过这个问题的答案吗
Any thoughts on the answer?
"愿意"  "不愿意"  "滚出我的生活  废物"
"Yes?", "No?", "Get out of my life, loser.",
都有可能
they're all possible.
我想我会选
I think I'll go for
愿意
"yes."
谢谢你跟我求婚
Thank you for asking me.
还要谢谢你没有搞得很戏剧性
And thank you for not going for one of those melodramatic proposals
一大群人围着的那种
with lots of people around.
我讨厌有别人
I hate other people.
我也是
Me, too.
对
Yeah.
我去把收音机关掉
I'm just gonna turn off the radio.
好的  好主意
Okay. Good idea.
谢谢大家  抱歉  她有点累
Thanks, guys. Sorry, she's a bit tired.
但是非常感谢  你们能走吗
But we really appreciate it. Can you go?
太美了
That's so beautiful.
可是我觉得我们不能住一个房间
I don't think we'll be staying in the same room, somehow.
真的吗
Really?
要是他们让你喝茶  就拒绝
If they offer you tea, just say no.
妈妈  这是玛丽
Mum, this is Mary.
玛丽
Mary!
我的天哪  你真漂亮
Good Lord, you're pretty.
不  我就是
No, it's just
妆画得比较浓
I've got a lot of mascara and lipstick on.
我看看
Let's have a look.
是哦  很好
Yes. Good.
女孩太漂亮不好
It's very bad for a girl to be too pretty.
太漂亮就没有幽默感  或者没特色
It stops her developing a sense of humour. Or a personality.
喝茶吗
Tea?
非常愿意
I'd love a cup of tea.
天哪  一整天的时间都要没了
Christ, that's the whole day gone.
她是位很特别的客人
She's a very special guest.
只要茶  不要饼干
Cup without the crack.
打水漂
Skipping stones.
他们从他这么高的时候就一直玩这个
They've been doing this since he was about this high.
你有什么缺点  就是小弱点
And what are your faults? I mean, little weaknesses.
我
I...
我非常没安全感
Well, I'm very insecure.
很好
Sweet.
好的  我有时候脾气很差
Okay. I've a very bad temper sometimes.
很重要  不然怎么让
Crucial. How else are you gonna
男人听你的呢
get a fella to do what you want?
当然  我还有一个软肋
And, of course, I have...
那就是你的儿子
I have a weakness for your son.
我也是
So do I.
但是最好别告诉他  别让他骄傲了
But best not to tell him. Don't want him getting cocky.
没球的时候我好厉害
I'm so good without the ball. Pow!
觉得她如何
What do you think of her?
比起你  我已经更喜欢她了
I like her more than you already.
意大利演员  编曲家及作词家
瞧  我都忘了这个  吉米·丰塔纳的《世界》
Look, I'd forgotten this. Jimmy Fontana Il Mondo.
脑袋上像顶了个死獾的意大利人
Greatest record ever recorded by an Italian
录得世界上最棒的唱片
who looks like he's got a dead badger on his head.
你还有唱片集
And you've got the album.
太好了
Yes!
看那眼镜
Check out those specs!
快点  比赛开始了  对
Come on, on with the game! Right.
多么出色的一场比赛
And what an extraordinary game this is.
世界乒乓大赛上
For the first time a father and son
第一次有父子对战
are playing each other in the World Table
他俩还都不是中国人
Tennis Final and neither of them are Chinese.
这是原世界冠军和他的儿子之间的终极对决
Tremendous play from the old World Champion and his son,
儿子是英国首位红发乒乓球手
the first openly ginger British table tennis player
但是年轻人已经显露出不敌对手的形势
but there are signs the youngster's beginning to crack.
-他眼中有泪  -并没有
- There are tears in his eyes. - There are not!
马上就有了
There soon will be!
我不知道你在
Hey! I didn't know you were here.
我刚下来
Yeah. I just popped down for a while.
好的
Okay.
工作呢
What about the job?
那你来了多久了
So how long have you been here?
几个星期
Couple of weeks.
那伦敦的生活呢
Gosh! So, life in London...
很糟糕
Horrid.
好的
Okay.
玛丽在吗
Is Mary here?
在
Yes.
哪里  楼下
Where? Downstairs.
你温柔点
You be gentle.
温柔点
Be gentle!
小心
Careful!
我也很高兴见到你  我在努力留个好印象
Yeah, nice to see you, too. I'm trying to make a good impression...
对  抱歉抱歉
Right, sorry. Sorry.
我有件重要的事要宣布
I've got an important announcement to make.
好兴奋
Exciting.
经过一点点考虑  我们决定要结婚
We've decided, after a little bit of thought, to get married.
真是个好消息
That's wonderful news.
你要跟谁结婚
Who are you getting married to?
跟玛丽  那个
To Mary. Over there.
谢天谢地
Thank God for that.
要是别的姑娘就尴尬了  你想想
Jolly embarrassing if it had been another girl. Imagine that.
我们太高兴了
We're so pleased.
不  对不起  对
No, sorry. Yeah.
顺便说一句  婚礼很快就举行了
By the way, the wedding will be quite soon
因为我们也快有孩子了
because we're having a baby, too.
你怀孕了吗
You're pregnant?
对
Yes.
谁的孩子
Who's the father?
我希望是蒂姆的
Well, Tim, I hope.
谢天谢地  要是喜当爹就尴尬了
Thank God for that. Jolly awkward if it had been another fellow.
我们得今晚决定
We have to decide tonight.
-什么  -所有事情
- What? - Everything.
我们的婚礼
The only thing you've decided about our
你唯一决定的事就是
wedding is that I'm coming down the aisle
我穿过教堂走到你跟前时
to the sound of some Italian weirdo
要放那个意大利怪人唱的《世界》
singing a song called Il Mondo.
多好的歌
Excellent song.
就是我说坚决不行的那首
To which I've said a definitive "no".
所以这样吧
So here's the deal.
你决定一件事  我就脱一件衣服
I will take off one item of clothing for every decision you make.
好的  我了解了  年轻的女士
Okay. You have my attention, young lady.
好的
Right, um,
你想在哪办婚礼
where would you like to get married?
家  我讨厌别的地方
Home. I'd hate anywhere else.
好的
Okay.
天哪  很好
My God. Good.
应该找哪位神父
Who should the priest be?
得是有一口黄牙
It'll have to be the local bloke
和一堆连心眉的当地人
with yellow teeth and the massive unibrow.
好的
Okay.
那就决定找海格
That's a lock for Hagrid.
伴郎呢
Best Man?
该死
Damn.
伴郎  快决定
Best Man. Now.
不  太难了  这是双输
No, this is so hard.
会气坏所有没选的人
It's lose-lose you know You piss off all the
最后还会憎恨你选的那个人
ones you don't pick, and you end up hating the one you do pick
因为他的演讲乱七八糟  把婚礼搞砸了
because he makes a bad speech and ruins the day.
你想不想见这对小可爱嘛
Do you wanna see these puppies or not?
想
Yes, I do.
-杰  -你决定
- Jay. - It's your choice.
他是我最好的朋友  但他是个傻子
He's my best friend, but he's a moron.
对  他会把所有事都搞砸
Yeah, he will mess up everything.
-罗利  -确定吗
- Rory. - Sure?
不  哈利吧
No, Harry.
那就哈利了  来吧
Harry it is. Let's do this.
罗利  抱歉
Rory. Sorry.
什么  真会作弊
What? That's such a cheat.
好吧
Okay, fine.
蜜月呢
Honeymoon?
去苏格兰  住小旅馆
Bed and breakfast in Scotland.
苏格兰可不值得让我脱掉小裤裤
I am not taking my pants off for Scotland.
但是我们的钱只够去那  快  脱掉内裤
But it's all we can afford. Take off your pants.
不脱
I will not.
脱掉内裤
Take off your pants!
我想去巴厘岛待两个星期
I want two weeks in Bali!
脱掉内裤
Take off those pants!
-你计划间歇了吗   -没有
- Have you planned a break? - No.
不  是你吗  不是我
No! Is that you? It wasn't me.
这是给你的
It's for you.
不  我被勾住了  我来我来
No, I'm caught! I've got it. I've got it!
帮帮我
Help me!
好
Yes!
对  跟着我
Right, follow me!
天哪
My gosh!
My God!
神哪
God!
真是个玩笑
It's a joke!
给
Here.
对  快来
Yes, come on.
这边
This way.
天哪
My God!
我是罗利
I'm Rory.
蒂姆让我当他的伴郎的时候  我吓坏了
When Tim asked me to be his Best Man, I was terrified.
所以我想最好是去找一本
So I thought best thing is to find
关于演讲的书  这本就是
a book about speeches. And here it is.
书上说想想有趣的轶事
And it says think of really funny anecdotes.
工作时候  有件非常好笑的事
And there is a very hilarious story, actually from work.
这个笑话基于一个挺复杂的案子
It was quite a complicated case based on an issue of
有关离婚后
cross-amortisation of ownership of
财产所有权跨摊销
post-divorce properties and, um...
我解释一下背景  被告...
Let me just explain the context. The Defendant...
蒂姆让我做伴郎演讲时
When Tim asked me to do his Best Man speech,
我当即的反应是
my immediate reaction was,
你要付我多少钱  小混球
"How much are you gonna pay me, you little shit?
我写的东西可得花钱买
"I don't write for free, you know."
这些是那时他有机可趁的姑娘们
These were the girls available to him at that time.
姑娘们好  而这是他跟她们的距离
"Hello, girls." And this is how far he got with each of them.
我来解释编号的含义  5代表口交
Let me explain the code. 5, blow job.
8代表完全深入...
8, full penetrative...
那么我们敬一杯
And so a toast
给这间屋子发型最糟糕
to the man with the worst haircut
但是人最好的新郎
but the best bride in the room.
女士们先生们  蒂姆和玛丽
Ladies and gentlemen, Tim and Mary.
蒂姆和玛丽
Tim and Mary.
是我们
That's us.
我要是说了"我爱你"就好了
I wish I'd said "I love you".
你说了  爸爸
You did, Dad.
话里的意思就是
It was implied.
我觉得婚礼上搞"话中话"不大好
I'm not sure "implied" is good enough for a wedding day, are you?
不  别那么做  这样就好
No, don't do it, it's fine.
现在这样我就很高兴  真的不用
I'm so happy with it as it was. You really don't have to.
我要按我想的做  小伙子
I'll do what I wanna do, young man.
我能先离开一下吗
Will you excuse me for just one moment?
待会儿我会给你们讲述
Later on I may tell you about
蒂姆作为男人以及乒乓球选手的许多失败故事
Tim's many failings as a man and as a table tennis player.
但是
But,
重要的是先说一件大事
important first to say the one
我一生中
big thing, I've only loved
只爱过三个男人
three men in my life.
我爸爸是个冷酷的讨厌鬼
My dad was a frosty bugger so that
所以第一位是亲爱的德斯蒙德叔叔
only leaves dear Uncle Desmond,
美国布鲁斯吉他手和歌曲作者  2003滚石杂志排名第三吉他手
最伟大的布鲁斯音乐家之一  外号"布鲁斯之王"
第二位当然是B·B·金
B.B. King, obviously,
还有就是这个小伙子
and this young man here.
我只给将结婚的人一条建议
I'd only give one piece of advice to anyone marrying.
我们最终都差不多
We're all quite similar in the end.
我们年华老去  境况大同小异
We all get old and tell the same tales too many times.
但是试着跟一个
But try and marry someone
善良的人结合
kind.
而这是一位有着好心肠的
And this is a kind man
善良男人
with a good heart.
我一生中没有很多
I'm not particularly proud
特别自豪的事  但是作为他的父亲
of many things in my life, but I am very proud
我十分自豪
to be the father of my son.
很抱歉打断你  但能跟你要个签名吗
I'm so sorry to disturb you, but I wonder if I could have your autograph.
不  不行
No. No.
我在婚礼上呢  老天啊
I'm at a wedding, for God's sake.
我在这里庆祝真爱  而不是
I'm here to celebrate true love not
在一张纸上随便签个名
scribble my illegible signature on stupid
好让你放到网上拍卖
bits of paper that you can flog on eBay
换点钱买个不这么丑的帽子戴
so that at the next wedding you can wear a less hideous hat.
你好像见过我的梅姑姑了
I see you've met my Aunt May.
神啊  大家要是都戴着姓名牌就好了
God. People should wear name tags.
下一个就是你了  琪凯
You next, Kittle Kattle.
我也不知道  D舅舅
I don't know, Uncle D.
男生对我都不怎么好
Boys aren't very nice.
真的吗  亲爱的
Aren't they, darling?
据我所知是这样的
Not in my experience.
他们永远都是随随便便的
They're always taking liberties,
不懂得报答别人
not giving much back in return.
-好吃  -是吗
- It's yummy. - Yeah?
我喜欢你说好吃的样子
I like the way you say 'yummy'.
你会不会希望我们当初挑了个晴朗的日子
Do you wish we'd picked another less wet day?
不会
No.
根本不会
Not for the world.
这就开始了
And so it begins.
丰富多彩的每日生活
Lots and lots of types of days.
多有趣
Fun!
叫波丝吧
Posy.
听你的
Posy she is.
世界上最漂亮的小姑娘
The most beautiful girl in the world.
想让爸爸抱了吧  我懂你的
You want your daddy. Yes, I know.
好嘞
Yeah.
没人能帮你做准备
No one can ever prepare you for
迎接即将到来的婴儿
what happens when you have a child.
当看到怀中的小孩子
When you see the baby in your arms
你就会明白现在这就是你的责任了
and you know that it's your job now.
你无法对未知的爱与恐惧做好心理准备
No one can prepare you for the love and the fear.
她真可爱
She's lovely.
你刚出生时可丑了
You were such an ugly baby.
不像小孩  像黑猩猩
More chimpanzee than child.
我还记得第一次见到你的时候
I remember the first time I saw you,
我很感谢上帝我们离伦敦动物园不远
I thanked God we were in
开车就到
driving distance of London Zoo.
来来  把这个小家伙抱过来
Come on, hand over the little bugger,
看看她会不会扭来扭去
let's see if she bounces.
当然啦  她肯定会扭
Yeah, she definitely will bounce.
看啊
Look.
她什么都做得到
She can do anything.
看啊  你好啊
Look. Hello.
小宝贝
Sweetheart.
你无法预料自己所爱的人们
No one can prepare you for the love
会感受到什么样的爱
people you love can feel for them.
而且也没法预料
And nothing can prepare you for
那些没生小孩的朋友们的冷漠
the indifference of friends who don't have babies.
想让杰叔叔抱抱吗
Do you wanna go to Uncle Jay?
不用了  谢谢  我这样很好
No, thanks, it's fine. It's great.
你还会惊讶这么快就得
And it's a shock how quickly you have to move
搬到一个费用不菲的的新家
to a new place you completely can't afford.
瞧这是什么
Look what we found.
快看它是谁
Look who it is!
亲爱的
Honey!
抱歉
Sorry.
突然之间  时空旅行好似毫无必要
Suddenly, time travel seems almost unnecessary,
因为生活中的其他部分都如此令人振奋
because every detail of life is so delightful.
它叫什么名字
What's his name?
霍勒斯  我猜的
Horace, I think.
那肯定就叫这个
Of course it is.
我听说  作为教父唯一的重点就是
Only one important thing for a godfather, I'm told,
永远不要给小孩买比它身体还小的礼物
never bring a present smaller than the child.
闭嘴吧  你这个自以为是的混蛋
Shut up, you smug bastard.
别担心了  我什么东西都没带
Don't worry, I didn't bring anything at all.
她不会注意到的  脑子还没发育呢
She'll never know. Hasn't got a brain yet.
没想到在这里能见到你  哈利
I didn't expect to see you here, Harry.
儿童聚会好像不是你的风格
Children's party's not exactly your style.
没错  玛丽  我被骗了
No, Mary, I was tricked.
他们跟我说有免费酒喝的
I was told there would be free booze.
我讨厌小孩子  你知道的
I hate kids, as you know.
话说奇巧去哪了
Where's Kit Kat, by the way?
不知道  她说3点左右过来
I don't know, she said she'd be here around 3:00.
你看我们还特别为她准备了紫色蛋糕
And you know we got purple cupcakes for her especially.
她来了
Here she is!
说曹操  曹操到
Speak of the devil, that will be her.
我们等奇巧姑姑来了再吃
We'll wait till Aunty Kit Kat gets here.
你好  吉米
Hey. Jimmy.
我妹妹呢
Where's my sister?
我还以为她在这里
Thought she was here.
没有  她还没到
No, she hasn't arrived.
这可不妙
That's not good.
你什么意思
What does that mean?
我们今天早上吵了一架
Um... We had an argument this morning.
就鸡毛蒜皮的小事  但她喝醉了
Over nothing, but she'd been drinking, so...
然后她就跑出家门开车来这
And then she ran out to get the car to come here and
我跟她说在这里碰面
I told her to meet me here so...
有一首巴兹·鲁尔曼的歌叫防晒霜
There's a song by Baz Luhrmann called Sunscreen.
他说对未来的事情担忧
He says worrying about the future
就像用嚼口香糖
is as effective as trying to solve
解方程式一样  毫无意义
an algebra equation by chewing bubble gum.
生活中真正的麻烦
The real troubles in your life
永远是你意料之外的事情
will always be things that never crossed your worried mind.
怎么了
What happened?
我们吵架了
We had a fight.
然后
And,
大概我还没有完全清醒
maybe I wasn't completely sober.
-她怎么样  -不太好
- How is she? - Not good.
她什么时候从哪里走的
When did she leave you? From where?
我要精确的时间和地址
I want it exact. Exact time. Exact address.
我们回来了  抱歉  抱歉
Here we are. Sorry, sorry.
来吧
Come on.
天啊
God.
-你好  -把她接来了
- Hi. - There she is.
小婴儿住在这里吗
Does a small baby live here?
在  她可兴奋了  就在楼下
Yes, and she's so excited. She's downstairs.
生日快乐  波丝
Happy birthday, Posy.
抱歉  我必须去接奇巧
I'm sorry. I had to pick up Kit Kat.
我以为她会自己开过来呢
I thought she was gonna drive herself.
结果还是不行
Turns out she couldn't.
-她没事吧  -再说吧
- She okay? - Later.
我很担心奇巧
I'm worried about Kit Kat.
我知道
Yeah. I know.
我们喝茶的时候她一个人狂灌红酒
She was drinking wine while we were drinking tea.
吉米对她不好
And Jimmy wasn't nice to her.
而且她根本对紫色蛋糕不理不睬
And she spurned the purple cupcakes.
我们得改变一下这个事实
We have to do something to fix it.
对
Yeah.
但是你要知道
But, you know,
就算要改变事实
if it's gonna be fixed,
也应该让她自己来改变
I think she probably has to do it herself.
也许是
Maybe.
也许不是
Maybe not.
亲爱的  发生了什么事
My darling. What's happened?
你是这个世界上最棒的人
You're the best person in the world.
对我来说和我妻子一样重要  我不懂你
You're top equal with my wife. I don't get it.
也许  只是也许
Maybe, just maybe,
我是个失败者
I'm the faller.
每个家族都有一个失败者
Every family has, like, someone who falls,
成绩差  不停犯错
who doesn't make the grade, who stumbles,
人生一团糟
who life trips up.
也许我就是咱家的失败者
Maybe I'm our faller.
不是这样的
No.
好吧  我要告诉你一个秘密
Okay. I'm gonna tell you a secret.
你得保证不会说出去
And you have to promise to keep it.
我们一直都互相保守秘密
We've always kept secrets.
是吗
We have?
你保证你永远  永远  永远
You promise you won't ever, ever, ever,
永远  永远  永远  永远
ever, ever, ever, ever,
永远  永远都不说出去吗
ever, ever, ever, ever tell?
好
Yes.
我能时空旅行
I can travel in time.
为什么咱们要站在楼梯下的柜橱里
Why are we standing in the cupboard under the stairs?
因为我们要回到过去
Because we're gonna go back in
让你对未来发生的事做出改变
time and you're gonna do some things differently.
我就喜欢你说笑话
I love it when you're funny.
抓住我的手  闭上眼睛
Grab my hand. Close your eyes.
上帝啊  上帝啊
My God! My God!
他妈见鬼的上帝啊
My arsing God in a box.
不是吧
You're kidding?
我可以回到任何时刻
I can go anywhere in time and
但你却偏偏把我带到史上最烂的一次聚会
you bring me back to the worst party of all time.
好像是  走吧
'Fraid so. Let's go.
我们还有事情要做
We've got work to do.
什么事
What work?
确保你不会遇见吉米·金凯德
Making sure you do not meet Jimmy Kincade.
快点  这里
Quick, in here.
但是他马上就要和我坠入爱河了
But he's about to fall in love with me!
这次不会了
Not this time he isn't.
这边的美女是谁啊  你叫詹妮弗是不是
Who's the pretty looking girl? It's Jennifer, isn't it?
是啊
Yeah.
真狂野
Wild!
我喜欢你的裙子  詹妮弗
I like your skirt, Jennifer.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧  我懂了
Right, I get it.
如果他没有遇到我
If he hadn't met me,
他就会找个别的女人上床
he would have just had sex with someone else.
要防患于未然吗
Nip it in the bud?
不好意思  吉米
Excuse me, Jimmy.
抱歉  我认识你吗
Sorry. Do I know you?
对  你认识
Yeah, you do.
咱俩很熟  抱歉
Very well. Sorry.
我打一开始就应该这么做的
And this is what I should have done right at the start.
新年快乐  各位  新年快乐
Happy New Year, everybody. Happy New Year.
快回柜橱里去
And back to the cupboard.
真惊人
Amazing!
然后会发生什么
What happens now?
天知道
God knows.
我只希望从现在开始
What I'm hoping is that from this moment on you avoid
你不会再招惹上这种肮脏小人了
the sleazy bad guys because they're sleazy and bad.
你什么时候变得这么严肃了
When did you get so serious?
自从我差点失去你那一次起
Since it occurred to me that I might lose you.
准备好  接下来可能很奇怪
Brace yourself, this could be weird.
一切都会被改变
Things will have changed.
上帝啊
My God.
什么
What?
是杰
Jay.
-你说的是那个杰吗  -对
- Jay Jay? - Yes.
他很迷人  天啊
And he's adorable. My God.
好吧
Right,
就这么办
let's do this.
你们俩快点
Come on, you two.
妈妈刚开了一包饼干
Mum's just cracked open a packet of biscuits.
我想起来有东西要给你
I've got something in mind for you.
我知道你准备说什么
I know what you're gonna say.
吃块饼干  然后来帮我个忙
Have a biscuit and come and help me.
剩下的留给D舅舅
But leave the rest for Uncle D.
其实只是收拾一下屋子
It's just tidying really.
-你还好吗  我很想你  -很好
- You all right? I missed you. - Yeah.
-你妈妈想让我去花园里帮忙  -好
- Your mum wants me to do some gardening. - Okay.
就是清理一下  长得乱糟糟的
It's tidying up, it's all a bit out of control.
所有死了的植物都清出去
Anything that looks dead, out.
我们要找这个  看到了吗  全部都要
This is what we're looking for. Okay? All this.
死掉的东西  看这个
Dead stuff. See this.
都被撕成碎片了  是不是
They've torn them to shreds, haven't they?
一切进展如何
How did everything go?
非常令人满意
Immensely satisfactory.
太好了  发生的所有事情都要告诉我
I'm so happy. I wanna hear all about it.
你能给我们做晚饭吗  因为我有点事
Will you do dinner for us because there's something
6点前必须完成  不然就要被炒了
I have to do before 6:00 or I'll get fired?
好的  乐意之至
Yeah. I can't think of anything I'd love to do more.
好啦  世界上最漂亮的小美人在哪里
Okay, where is the most fabulous person in the world?
过来让爸爸喂你吃米粉糊糊
Come to your dad and get mashed up food shoved into your mouth!
你好啊  小伙子
Hello there, little boy.
你就
You just
站在这里不要动  我马上回来
wait there and I'll be back in a minute.
爸  我能跟你稍微谈一下吗
Dad, can I have a quick word?
好的  没问题
Yeah. Sure.
我不能回到出生以前的时间了  是不是
I can't go back past the birth again, can I?
不行  我应该跟你说的
No. I should have mentioned that.
出生之前都没关系  但那个特定的时间点
You're okay till it comes out but the exact
一个特定的精子让你们有了
sperm at the exact moment got you this
这个孩子
particular baby,
所以如果你造成了任何一点细微变化
so if you do anything the tiniest bit
你生出来的孩子就会不同
different, you'll have a different child.
那昨天以前就再也不能变了吗  定格了
So, every day up 'til yesterday is as it will always be? Lost?
和其他人一样
Just like for everyone else.
好吧  很有意思
Okay. Interesting.
真难办  我爱你  爸爸  我得走了
Tough. I love you, Dad. I've gotta go.
回去吧
Go home.
除非能保证这种事情再也不发生
We're not leaving this room until we find
否则我们绝对不会离开这个房间一步
a way of making sure this never happens again.
你们现在该走了吧
Will you go now?
我必须得离开吉米  是不是
I have to leave Jimmy, don't I?
永远
For good.
而且我得戒酒
And I have to stop drinking.
而且不能再随便换工作了
And stop leaving jobs.
而且我要和一个无聊的好人
And I have to go out with someone
谈恋爱
nice and boring.
终于觉悟了
Yay.
对了  好人不一定无聊
And, you know, nice isn't necessarily boring.
比如?
Like who?
马特·达蒙
Matt Damon?
好耶
Okay.
我会和马特·达蒙约会的
I'll go out with Matt Damon.
跟我讲  你最近见过杰吗
Tell me, have you seen Jay recently?
你的那个头发翘翘的杰吗
Your Jay? What, sticky-up hair Jay?
看起来就像个提线木偶的杰吗
Looks a bit like a muppet Jay?
对
Yes.
我突然想到了他  他一直对你很有好感
He just popped into my head. He's always had a crush on you.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Yeah.
好诡异
Weird!
考虑一下约他吃晚饭  你有时间吗
Thinking of asking him to dinner. Are you free?
可能吧  也许得先梳妆打扮一下
Might be. Might have to freshen up a bit first.
没错  你看起来惨死了
Yeah. You look shit.
乔安娜
Joanna.
感谢上帝  你们终于回来了
Thank Christ you're back.
这就是一场恶梦
It's been a total nightmare.
我懂  不过没关系的
I know. It's all fine anyway.
她在哪里
Where is she?
这是我这辈子最糟糕的一晚
It was the single worst night of my life.
波丝在哪里
Where's Posy?
找到啦  你好啊
There she is! Hello!
你好啊  你好
Hello! Hello.
亲爱的  你怎么样啊
Darling, how are you doing?
咱再生一个吧
Let's have another one.
去死吧  不要
Screw that. No.
生孩子很疼的  而且会变胖  肥得流油
That hurt and I got fat. Like fat-fat.
只胖了一点点  不是吗
Got a little bit fat, didn't she.
跟妈妈说你想要个小妹妹
Tell Mummy you want a sister.
不要  跟爸爸说你当独生女很高兴
No. Tell Daddy you're happy being an only child.
幸运的是  我们都还是无所顾忌的年轻人
Fortunately we are young and careless and
不久之后我们就变成了四口之家
it wasn't long before there were four of us.
不可思议  只有三岁的波丝·莱克
And this is incredible. Posy Lake, only 3 years old,
马上就打破女子10米跑的奥运会纪录了
is about to break the women's 10 metre Olympic record.
他们会成功的  他们跑过来了
They're gonna do it. And here they are,
他们做到了  了不起
they've done it! Fantastic.
你太棒了  表现真好
That was brilliant. You're so good.
这么吵都没被吵醒
Sleeping right through all that.
能帮个忙吗  我好紧张
Can you help me? I'm so nervous.
我们跟畅销书作者吃饭时穿什么比较好
What do I wear for dinner with our bestselling author?
先让我把怪兽画完  我就马上上去
Let me finish up with the monsters and I'll come right up.
好极了  谢谢
Great. Thank you.
继续
Go again.
好啦  这件怎么样
Okay. How about this?
很漂亮  任务完成  很好
That's gorgeous. Job done. Yeah.
不行  认真点挑  这个
No. Take it seriously. It's...
我不确定  不行  我不喜欢
I don't know. No, I hate it.
-没错  -这件没有亮点
- Yeah. - It's boring and
而且让我看起来疙疙瘩瘩的
makes me look kind of lumpy.
没错  你说得对
No, you're right.
确实没亮点  又都是疙瘩  我不喜欢
It is boring and lumpy. I hate it.
好吧  那这件呢
Okay. What about this?
美极了  就是它了
Gorgeous. We did it.
不行  胸露太多了
No, it's too breasty.
-是吗  -好吧
- Is it? - Okay.
这件没有很显胸
It's not too breasty.
不行  这双高跟鞋不能穿  看起来像妓女
No. I'm not wearing these heels. I look like a prostitute.
那就别穿高跟鞋了
Not high heels, then.
但是那样又会让腿显得很短
But then we have the short legs problem.
那你是想看起来像妓女还是矮子
Well, do you want to look like a prostitute or a dwarf?
小心  小心点说话
Warning. That's a warning.
很好
Yes!
不好
No.
不行
No!
这件我喜欢
Now that I like.
不是  我还在挑裙子
No, I'm just picking up the dress
这件是打底的  你真是个坏人
that this goes under. Such a bad boy.
这一件呢
This one?
不算太坏
Not bad.
还有这一件呢
Or this one?
-你在考我吧  这是同一件  -不是
It's a trick question, isn't it? Same dress. - No!
不是吗
No?
好啦  我觉得这件还不赖
Okay. I don't think this one's too bad.
没错  很漂亮
Yeah, it's fabulous.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Yeah.
好吧  不错
Okay. Great. Good.
那件蓝色的怎么样
How about the blue one?
- 蓝色的  -是啊
- The blue one? - Yeah.
行啊
Yeah.
你是说没亮点又疙瘩的那件吗
The first one that you tried on that was boring and lumpy,
而实际上  它很惊艳  也不疙瘩
but that wasn't actually boring and lumpy,
是那件吗
that one?
对的  你觉得哪件好
Yeah, which do you prefer?
我不知道  跟你说  我快疯了
I don't know. I'm actually starting to go mad.
我貌似还是喜欢蓝色那件
I think I like the blue one.
-好吧  -就这样
- Okay. - Yeah.
好了好了  我还是穿这件走
Okay. Okay, let's go with this one, then?
你美翻了
You look amazing.
-真的吗  -真心的
- Really? - Yes.
那多谢了
Okay, thanks.
我的天啊
God.
波丝哪去了
Where's Posy?
我让她呆在楼下呢
I left her downstairs.
我放手稿那屋的门关了吧
Not leaving the door open to the room with the manuscript in it?
貌似没有
I don't think so.
看着我  看着我的眼睛
Look at me. Look me in the eye.
告诉我怎么办
And talk me through this.
-我离死不远了  -好啦
- Basically my life is over. - OK.
我出去两分钟  也许一分钟就够
I really need to go out for just like two minutes, maybe one.
你敢
Don't you dare!
你敢接  我该怎么办
Don't you dare answer that! What am I gonna do?
我觉得我们真的该接电话了
I think that we should really answer the phone.
你要是接了那鬼电话
If you answer the goddamn phone,
我就用电话砸死你
I will kill you with the phone.
我不接电话  但是我真的要出去一下
I won't answer the phone, but I do need to get out.
不行  不准出去  不准  不行
No, no getting out, no getting out. No.
好吧
Okay, right.
抱歉啊  麦克尤恩先生
Sorry, Mr McEwan.
您的作品我们看了一大部分了  但是吧
We read most of your book but,
剩下那些有的染了色  有的碎成了渣
you see, the rest of it was coloured on or shredded.
对的
Yeah.
我没想到波丝会用碎纸机
I had no idea Posy actually knew how to use that machine
这么想来  还挺值得高兴的
in a way that's impressive.
干嘛啊  有什么事
What is it? How can I help you?
是玛丽啊
Oh, Mary.
不是的  一切都...抱歉
No, everything... Sorry.
让你儿子解释吧
Your son will explain.
是你老妈
It's your mother.
喂  妈
Hi, Mum.
不不不  没事  我们...
No, no, it's okay. We'll...
我们马上就去
We'll come straight down.
好的  再见
Okay, bye-bye.
回来啦  亲爱的
Hello, darling.
妈妈  你好吗
Mum. How are you?
想听真话吗
Honestly?
当然
Why not?
气死我了
I am fucking furious.
没你爸爸的生活索然无味啊
I am so uninterested in a life without your father.
玛丽  走吧  我们泡点茶去
Mary. Come on, let's make some tea.
你还好吗
How are you?
挺好的
Yeah, I'm fine.
吃饭了吗
Did you eat?
吃了的
Yes, of course.
德斯蒙德
Desmond.
您过得如何
How are you?
我很好  谢谢关心
I'm very well, thanks.
就是有点热
Though a little hot.
你爸可能不太好
Your father, I think, is not so well.
得了癌症
Cancer.
是啊
Yes.
蒂姆  我真的很难过
I'm very unhappy about it, Tim.
他在你婚礼上说他爱我
At your wedding he said he loved me.
-他确实很爱你  -我知道的
- He does. - I know.
那是我今生最美好的日子
That was the best day of my life.
今天可能是最糟糕的日子
So this is probably the worst.
爸
Dad.
我的上帝
For God's sake.
你也来这套
Not you, too.
什么
What?
奇巧刚刚哭着走了
Well, Kit Kat's just rolled up blubbing her eyes out
现在你又来了
and now you're here.
妈妈怎么跟你说的
What's Mum been saying?
实话实说的
The truth.
好吧
Yeah, well,
还说什么了
apart from that?
可能是抽烟造成的
It may have been the smoking
但这个我改变不了
but I couldn't undo that
因为在你们出生前我就抽烟了
as it was before you were all born.
不管怎么说
And anyway,
要不是我抽烟的样子特别帅
your mother definitely wouldn't have gone out with me
你妈绝对不会跟我谈恋爱的
if I hadn't been such a sexy smoker.
我这发现的也算早的了
I did get diagnosed as soon as possible,
但还是太晚了
but it was too late.
还有多少日子
How long have we got?
可能  可能几年吧
You know, it, it could be years.
到底多久
How long really?
恐怕也就几周
Weeks, I'm afraid.
我们以前是不是有过这个对话了
Have we had this conversation before?
是的
Yeah.
然后发生了什么
What happened?
我很难过
I rather let myself down.
我拥抱了你
I hugged you.
抱歉
Sorry.
我刚在考虑时间旅行的问题
I think I just thought with the time thing...
不行  我从没说过我们能修正生活
No, I never said we could fix things.
我绝对没那么说过
I specifically never said that.
生活总是喜忧参半  无论你是谁
Life's a mixed bag, no matter who you are.
拿耶稣来说  他是神的儿子
Look at Jesus. He was the Son of God,
就算看在上帝份上吧
for God's sake,
但是你看他结局怎样
and look how that turned out.
我知道的  但是...
I know, but...
我还是想说  我觉得有点受骗了
you must see I feel a bit cheated.
别那么想
Don't.
实际上  你可以换个角度
In fact, feel the opposite.
唯一一个50岁就退休的人
The only people who give up work at 50
就是这个身患绝症的时空旅人
are the time travellers with cancer
他还想和儿子多打打乒乓球呢
who want to play more table tennis with their sons.
是啊
Right.
就这么换位思考吗
So that's been the deal?
很抱歉  我们必须得打给你
I'm sorry we had to call.
因为病情突然恶化了
It's suddenly got very bad.
可我还有很重要的事要告诉你
And I have something very important to tell you.
或者说  我看看
Or, let me check,
你是想让我告诉你这个大秘密呢
do you want to know the big secret,
还是像我一样自己去发现
or would you rather find it out for yourself like I did?
天啊  又有一个什么秘密
Christ, there's another secret?
没那么离奇  但是重要得多
Less dramatic. Much more important.
真正的重头戏
The real mothership.
继续说吧  告诉我
No, go on. Tell me.
我们别浪费时间了
Let's save some time.
于是他告诉了我他关于幸福的秘密公式
And so he told me his secret formula for happiness.
这个规划分两部分  第一部分是
Part one of the two part plan
我应该恢复正常的生活
was that I should just get on with ordinary life,
一天一天的过  和普通人一样
living it day by day, like anyone else.
这是我们目前的陈词
This is our current statement
修正了一段  标出来了
with a revised paragraph there, highlighted.
鲁伯特
Rupert.
鲁伯特  这就是你最好的水平了么
Rupert, is that the best you can do?
不  当然不是了  我们可以再改改
No. Absolutely not. We can change that.
第二条款
Item number two.
-你好  -下午好  先生
- Hi. - Good afternoon, sir.
您今天是在这儿吃还是带走
Are you eating in or taking away today?
带走吧  谢谢
Take away, please.
是吗  没问题
Yeah? No problem.
好了  一共4镑24便士 先生
Lovely, that's 4.24 then,  please, sir.
谢谢惠顾
Thank you kindly.
好了  找您76便士  先生
Lovely. And there's your change, sir. 76 pence change.
-谢谢  -慢走  您好
- Thanks. - Thank you. Hello there.
您是在这儿吃还是带走
Are you eating in or taking away?
据你调查
Do you find the Defendant,
被告约翰·维尔贝克是否犯了诈骗罪
John Welbeck, guilty or not guilty of fraud?
无罪
Not guilty.
-这是你们所有人的裁决吗  -对
- And that is the verdict of you all? - Yes.
谢谢  你可以坐下了
Thank you. You may be seated.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
释放被告
Let the Defendant be discharged.
全体起立
Be upstanding in court.
-关灯吗  -好
- Lights out? - Yeah.
真是艰难的一天
Tough day.
然后是爸爸幸福规划的第二部分
But then came part two of Dad's plan.
他让我每一天都重新过一遍
He told me to live every day again
尽量和第一遍一样
almost exactly the same.
第一遍充斥着各种压力和忧虑
The first time with all the tensions and worries that
让我们忽略了这个世界美好的一面
stop us noticing how sweet the world can be,
但是在第二遍里  我去发现这些美好
but the second time noticing.
好了  爸爸
Okay, Dad.
我们来试试吧
Let's give it a go.
我们现在的陈词是什么
What's our statement at the moment?
在这儿  修改了...
This is it with the revised...
我知道一切不尽人意
I know it doesn't seem that way
鲁伯特  这个不行
Rupert, this does not pass.
这就是你最高水平了
Is this the best you can do?
但也许当前就是最好的时光
But maybe it's the perfect day
你俩把这玩意搞定
I'll leave you two to thrash this out.
他就是个傻逼
就算账单如山
Even though the bills are piling
也没有幸运女神临幸
And maybe Lady Luck ain't smiling
-下午好  先生  -下午好
- Good afternoon, sir. - Good afternoon.
今天在这吃还是带走
Are you eating in or taking away today?
带走吧
Take away.
要口袋吗
Would you like a bag?
拿一个吧
That's fine.
但是只要我们勇于面对
But if we'd  only open our eyes
好了  一共6磅23便士
Lovely. That's 6.23 then, please.
祝您愉快
And enjoy the rest of your day.
谢谢  再见
Thank you. Bye-bye.
您好
Hello, there.
就会发现上帝在默默庇护
We'd see the blessings in disguise
-你看周围  -怎么了
- Look around you! - What?
积云成雨  汇集成河
That all the rain clouds are fountains
这里是不是很漂亮
Isn't this room beautiful?
是啊
Yeah.
快走吧
Come on.
尽管困难如山
Though our troubles seem like mountains
无罪
Not guilty.
风雨过后  终现阳光
There's gold in them hills
太棒了
Fantastic!
风雨过后  终现阳光
There's gold in them hills
所以不要沮丧  不要灰心
So don't lose heart
给今天一个重新开始的机会
Give the day a chance to start
风雨过后  终现阳光
There's gold in them hills
所以今天过得还不赖
So not such a bad day after all?
是啊  很不错的一天
No. it was pretty good really.
实际上  今天很棒
Very good day, actually, as it turns out.
这给我减轻负担了
Well, that's a relief,
如果你今天过得很糟的话
because if it had been a very bad day,
我可能还得和你做个爱
I thought I might have had to have had sex with you
来调整一下你的情绪
to make up for it.
晚安
Goodnight.
今天过得糟透了
It was a very, very bad day.
简直糟到爆
It went very, very badly.
我被炒了鱿鱼
I got fired from my job.
还杀了一个人
And then I killed a man.
那可真够糟的
That is a very bad day.
-糟透了  -是啊
- It's terrible. - Yeah.
史上最倒霉的一天
Like the worst day ever.
我真为你难过
So sorry.
当然了
Some days, of course,
有些日子  你不想经历第二次
though, you only want to go through once.
你还好吗
You okay?
我不相信干涉主义的上帝
I don't believe in an interventionist God
但我知道  亲爱的你相信
But I know darling, that you do
如果我相信  我就跪下来请求他
But if I did I would kneel down and ask him
好了  都准备好了吗
Right, are we ready for this?
当然没有  不想经历这种悲痛时刻
'Course we're not. Hateful day.
对你不要干涉
Not to intervene when it came to you
等我一分钟
Just give me one minute.
你的一根头发都不要触碰
Oh, not to touch a hair on your head
让你保持本来的样子
Leave you as you are
如果他觉得你需要指引
If he felt he had to direct you
就指引你到我怀中
Then direct you into my arms
写得太棒了
This is so brilliant.
狄更斯对插科打诨真是在行
Dickens is so good on actual jokes, actual gags.
你从哪来的
Where have you come from?
是...
It's the...
我明白了
Oh, okay.
那个重要的日子
Big day.
谢谢你来看我
Thanks for dropping in.
德斯蒙德叔叔的西装怎么样
How's Uncle Desmond's suit?
完美无瑕
Immaculate.
很好
Excellent.
我提过我想放尼克·凯夫的歌吗
Did I mention I wanted the Nick Cave track?
都记着呢
It's taken care of.
谢谢啦
Thank you.
我给你读读这一小段行吗
Can I just read you this one bit?
尽管读吧  我有的是时间
Read away, I've got lots of time.
我想  古代的罗马人相互激怒结怨
"I think the Romans must have aggravated
一定是因为彼此的鼻子
"one another very much with their noses.
也许正是由于这个原因
"Perhaps they became
罗马人成了历史上一个不安分守己的民族
"the restless people they were in consequence.
无论如何
"Anyhow,
沃甫赛先生那罗马人的鹰钩鼻也激怒了我
"Mr Wopsle's Roman nose so aggravated me..."
到我怀中  上帝
Into my arms, oh Lord
到我怀中
Into my arms
但我相信有爱
But I believe in love
我知道你也相信
And I know that you do too
我相信有一条路
And I believe in some kind of path
我们可以同行  你和我
That we can walk down, me and you
燃着你的蜡烛
So keep your candles burning
让她的旅程纯净明亮
Make her journey bright and pure
把回来的路铭记于心
That she will keep returning
永远铭记
Always and evermore
到我怀中  上帝
Into my arms, oh Lord
到我怀中
Into my arms
孩子的事  你有什么看法
What do you think about the kids?
他们怎么了
What about them?
不够多吧  是不
Not many of them, are there?
什么
What?
我是说  两个太少了
Well, I mean two?
在中国就算超生了
It's more than the Chinese are allowed.
我就是想吧  也许
I just thought that maybe, you know,
我们该再生一个  以防万一
it was time for the insurance baby.
以防什么万一
What?
以防万一某个孩子特别聪明
In case one of them is really smart,
我们不希望另一个孩子
we don't want the other one
一辈子都觉得自己很笨
to feel stupid their whole life.
如果我们生了第三个
And if we had a third one,
两个小傻瓜就能快乐地作伴了
then we could have two happy dummies.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
这是我一生中最艰难的决定
It was the toughest decision of my life.
迎接新生意味着
Saying 'yes' to the future meant
与爸爸的永别
saying 'goodbye' to my dad. Forever.
我们为什么不再等等呢
Why don't we wait a bit?
当然了
Absolutely.
你说的没错
You're right. Yeah.
是现在呢
How about now?
还是现在呢
Or now?
现在吧
Now?
好吧
Yeah.
我同意
Okay.
真的吗
Really?
爸爸一直希望我们再要个孩子
Dad always wished there had been more of us.
所以...
So...
不过  我们也不一定能怀上
Anyway, we might try and nothing happens.
确实
Exactly.
可能今晚就要生了
Really could be tonight.
你绝对想象不到
And you cannot believe the detail in which
我多熟悉去医院的路
I know the route to the hospital.
是啊
Yay.
你能等我一下吗
Will you excuse me for a sec?
我下趟楼
Just have to go downstairs.
现在比分17比20  比赛十分激烈
And it's 17-20 in this incredibly tight contest
两位运动员都是
being played by the two most physically
史上最佳的选手
perfect players in the history of the game.
观众为年轻选手而着迷
The crowd, enchanted by the younger player, are seduced
也被老选手的辉煌过去所吸引
by memories of the older player's illustrious past.
天啊  我赢了
My God, I've won.
我多少年没赢过了
I haven't won in years.
你可总算赢了
You finally got good.
该给我颁什么奖
What's my prize?
当然了  除了奥运会金奖以外
Apart from the Olympic gold medal, of course.
给你一个吻
A kiss will have to do.
一个吻?
A kiss?
我明白了
I get you.
到时间了吧
This is it, then?
到时间了
This is it.
这是我最后的一点时间了
It's my last bit of extra time.
孩子马上就要出生了
The baby is completely on the way.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
我的儿子
My son.
我的爸爸
My dad.
有什么我能做的
Is there anything at all I can do?
有什么你想做的
Is there anything you want to do?
我不知道  就有这么...
I don't know. There is this...
一件事
one thing.
去散个小步
A quick little walk.
当然了  这是完全违背规则的
Totally against the rules, of course,
但是如果我们不做任何改变
but if we don't change a thing,
足够小心的话  就没什么事
if we're very careful, it shouldn't do any harm.
会很棒的
It would be nice.
我尽力了  我真的尽力了
I'm really trying. I'm really trying.
低一点
Get down low.
我完胜你
Total defeat.
我累了
I'm tired.
谢谢你  爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
我的故事也快讲完了
So I'm almost up-to-date with my story.
和别的家庭一样
As all families do,
我们渐渐适应了亲人离世后的生活
we got used to life after death.
过得依然很好
And it was still fine.
日复一日
And things settled back into their traditional rhythms
一切都回到正轨
season after season,
和过去一样
and are much as they have always been.
我们也适应了奇巧重新快乐起来的样子
And we've got used to Kit Kat being happy again.
然后适应了她当妈妈的样子
And then we got used to her being a mum.
虽然她这个妈妈不是特别称职
Albeit not a very good
甚至很没安全感
or even safe one.
最后的最后
And in the end,
我学到了我时光旅行的最后一课
I think I've learned the final lesson from my travels in time.
我甚至还比我爸爸更进了一步
And I've even gone one step further than my father did.
好吧  我去照顾孩子
Okay, I'll do the kids.
不用  别担心  我会去的
No, don't worry. I'll do them.
好  你来  你个懒蛋
Yeah, you do them, you lazy bum.
实际上  我现在从不穿越回过去
The truth is, I now don't travel back at all.
一天也不
Not even for the day.
我努力过好每一天
I just try to live every day
就像我已经穿越回去一样
as if I've deliberately come back to this one day
我努力享受每一天
to enjoy it
就像它是我这平凡又非凡生命的
as if it was the full final day
最后一天
of my extraordinary, ordinary life.
很多事情不能一次成功
I don't get many things right the first time
人们总是对我这样说
In fact, I am told that a lot
如今我知道
Now I know all the wrong turns
是那些过失带我走到今天
The stumbles and falls brought me here
哎呀  你都已经下来啦
Hello, you're down already.
做得太好了  谢谢喽
That's great. Thank you so much for that.
我们坐进来吧
And in we go.
那天之前  我在哪里
And where was I before the day
波丝  波丝
Posy? Posy!
那是第一次见到你美丽的脸
That I first saw your lovely face?
如今可以每天相见
Now I see it everyday
很美味的
That's fine.
于是我知道
And I know that I am
我就是最幸运的人
I am, I am the luckiest
我们生命的每一天
We're all travelling through time together
都是在时间中的旅行
every day of our lives.
我们所能做的就是
All we can do is
尽我们所能
do our best
珍惜这段美妙的旅程
to relish this remarkable ride.
对对对
Yes, yes, yes...
好的  到时候见
Okay, I'll see you then.
拜拜啦
Bye-bye.
等下见
See you later.
剧  终